<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Sumilang on Richard Sumilang </title>
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 66 Aug 40633 06:06:06 PST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vi Vante Review</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 66 Aug 40633 06:06:06 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Ooo hello there Matador Noir! Now that’s a good looking strap.” &amp;hellip; “What?!? $250!!! For a camera strap???” Yeah, those were my exact thoughts when I first laid my eyes on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/matador-noir&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Matador Noir&amp;quot; The World&#39;s Most Luxurious Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Matador Noir”&lt;/a&gt;. I glanced at a few pictures and thought &lt;em&gt;yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty nice&lt;/em&gt;. Glanced at the price, sighed, and closed my browser tab. A year has passed since then and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; camera straps have been my exclusive choice of leather on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2XXqZAm&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10&#34;&gt;Leica M&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Q&lt;/a&gt; bodies. But how did this happen? How did I let this seemingly overpriced looking brand take over my precious Leica collection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, it was quite obvious. I never really found the perfect camera strap for my Leica cameras. Like most people, I started off with whatever came with the camera. My first Leica was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; that I picked up at a sketchy pawn shop. It came with a nice silky rope strap which was ok, not really me, but I ran with it anyways. As you know, get one Leica and it won’t be your last&amp;hellip; I then got a M3 that came with guitar style strap. It was very hippie and not really me either. At this point I started experimenting with various leather straps. Short, long, adjustable, with a pad, anything and everything. You name it, I had it. The Leica infection I had was spreading simultaneously and once I believed I needed a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2XXqZAm&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt;, well I got one. Not impressed with the standard strap, I went to a Leica gallery and picked what looked like should be a great strap that a sales person had to pull from behind the glass shelves. It was popular German brand (I won’t mention their name) I see at a lot of Leica galleries so I figure it should be decent. Spent about $169.00 + taxes. It was made from a nice whiskey leather, had a decent pad that was big enough to not feel the weight of the Leica choking you yet thin enough to keep that slim look. It was supple out of the box unlike other straps that required a break in period. It was perfect until not too long after the threading started to frail. This became annoying if you could imagine having to trim the loose ends every so often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if this well established German brand couldn’t make camera straps right, then who is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; to think they can come and solve all the problems I’ve been having? I had my doubts and was skeptical to buy a high priced strap from them with no reviews to be found online. But a the same time I&amp;rsquo;ve been wondering what does a camera strap demanding over $200 feel like? I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s literally a strap with rings at each end right? But who am I to judge especially what I paid for a manual Leica camera? I opened a dialog to them and they seemed very responsive and easy to talk to which was the first green light. However, time for me was running short because I was soon to be going on a vacation and I didn’t want to use my existing straps. The one that requires an occasionally trim just looks bad and the others were just too thin that caused neck and shoulder pain like someone is trying to choke you with a piano wire if you tried wearing them longer than hour. I needed something that could last me a whole day of being a tourist without causing neck or shoulder discomfort. I needed to be able to wear my camera all day and have it by my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi Vante replied and suggested the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/matador-noir&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Matador Noir&amp;quot; The World&#39;s Most Luxurious Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Matador Noir”&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ultime-blackout&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Ultime&amp;quot; Blackout Braided Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Ultime”&lt;/a&gt; would be fine with my M bodies and Summilux lenses. In a pinch, I ordered both, one from Amazon and one directly from Vi Vante because I was worried one wouldn’t get to me before I depart to Europe. I thought I would just keep whichever one arrived first and probably return the other. However their shipping was extremely fast and both straps arrived to me at nearly the same time leaving much time to spare. They came in a nice little box with beautiful wrapping. The strap was in the box in a nice custom pouch. Basically packaged the way you should expect when purchasing luxury items. I pulled them out and was amazed at the quality as soon as I touched the leather! It was amongst, if not, the softest and most supple leathers I have ever felt. How they are able to achieve such a thick and tight braid while keeping the straps free forming is impressive to say the least. I find products that require a break in period first (like some shoes) are kind&amp;rsquo;ve annoying. A great product to me is something that is ready out of the box and only gets better with time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; delivered precisely that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate further, the straps can easily be wrapped around your wrist or crumbled in your palm without much resistance and easily fall back into their natural shape when released. The leather doesn’t require your body oil and sweat to be massaged into it for months to soften it and give character as they say. The under side of the strap which lays on your body is just as beautiful as the top because there are clearly no shortcuts taken. The straps being so flexible have actually made it easy for me to toss my camera in a bag without it being a nuisance. The width is just right for up to a Summilux lens and can makes your camera setup feel almost weightless with a Summicron. (I don’t have any Notctiluxes to test with.) And how many of you have your black Leica, black lens, black camera strap, but break your continuity with silver camera strap rings? I thought that was an annoying thing only I cared about but all &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; straps come with electroplated gun metal rings! Isn’t that the icing on the cake or what? It seems like a small detail but if you’re reading this and you’re a Leica shooter then you know its all about the small details and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; gets it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One minor shortcoming is their straps are all 49” long. I’m 5”11 and that actually works for me pretty well. I thought I’d miss the ability to jack up my camera to my arm pits when I’m in “action mode”. I usually compensate by either throwing my camera in my sling or wrap the strap around my wrist snake style. My fiancé however is about 5”4 and the straps are a bit too long for her&amp;hellip; Sorry short people. On the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s kind&amp;rsquo;ve nice because I didn&amp;rsquo;t always like how the slider looked on my shirt especially when it was metal thus making it attention grabing. Like a Leica, these straps are extremely simple to use so there is no need to fiddle with anything while being a design masterpiece at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I ended up keeping both straps for my trip and applied the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ultime-blackout&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Ultime&amp;quot; Blackout Braided Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Ultime”&lt;/a&gt; to my m3 and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/matador-noir&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Matador Noir&amp;quot; The World&#39;s Most Luxurious Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Matadoir Noir”&lt;/a&gt; to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2XXqZAm&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10&#34;&gt;m10&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Yeah, yeah I’m one of those guys who brings multiple cameras on a vacation. I know, I can’t help it. I’m getting better though, I promise :) Fast forward to today, I’m the proud owner of more Vi Vante straps than I have Leicas. I’ve added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ultime-phoenix&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Ultime Phoenix Red Black Braided Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Ultime Phoenix”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ascari/nardo&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Ascari Nardo Gray Napa Leather 47&amp;quot; Camera Strap&#34;&gt;“Ascari Nardo Gray”&lt;/a&gt;, and my new current favorite&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3cD09mx&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Tiger Braided Luxury Lambskin Leather&#34;&gt;“The Tiger Luxury Lambskin”&lt;/a&gt;. You just have to feel that lambskin leather. I’m all about the supple leathers and this feels as flexible as a cotton strap. Unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re a wrist strap person, then I have to say yes they&amp;rsquo;ve also made the best wrist strap I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/374A3r9&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Bengal Unleashed Black Leather Camera Wrist Strap Ultra Soft Lambskin&#34;&gt;ViVante Bengal Unleashed&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s basically &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3cD09mx&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Tiger Braided Luxury Lambskin Leather&#34;&gt;The Tiger&lt;/a&gt; strap shortened for your wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other little perks of having a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante strap&lt;/a&gt;. It’s hard to explain but it brings me joy when seeing how the strap falls beautifully around the camera when setting it down on a table. It’s a small thing but if you own one of these straps then you might understand what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you’re an admirer of the Leica’s precision, design, and have been yearning for a camera strap to finally match the standards that it demands, then look no further. I don’t think you’ll be dissatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/vi-vante-tiger-richard-coffee.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/vi-vante-tiger-richard-steps.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/vi-vante-tiger-richard-wrapped.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinestill C-41 Development Times</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/chemicals/cinestill-c41-developer-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 56 Aug 240553 05:05:05 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/chemicals/cinestill-c41-developer-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find my table of development times for color negative film using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freestylephoto.biz/800341-CineStill-Cs41-Liquid-Developing-Kit-for-C-41-Color-Film-1-Quart&#34; title=&#34;CineStill Cs41 Liquid Developing Kit for C-41 Color Film - 1 Quart&#34;&gt;Cinestill C-41 kit&lt;/a&gt; at 102 degrees F. These notes should work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2X1InEV&#34; title=&#34;Arista C-41 kit&#34;&gt;Arista C-41&lt;/a&gt; as well since the instructions are nearly identical for chemical reuse. Heck, it might even be the same stuff, just repackaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s handy to print this out and save it in your lab for quick references. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to put a piece of &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36pujrR&#34; title=&#34;Gapher tape&#34;&gt;gapher tape&lt;/a&gt; on your &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eaOjAU&#34; title=&#34;Amber boston round chemistry bottles&#34;&gt;chemistry bottles&lt;/a&gt; used for storage and mark how many rolls have been developed with them by a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2TBjj5j&#34; title=&#34;Sharpie permanent markers&#34;&gt;sharpie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table-bordered table-center&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Rolls Processed&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;i&gt;new chemistry&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:30&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:34&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:38&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:43&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:47&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:51&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:30&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:59&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:04&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:08&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:12&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:16&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:25&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:29&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:33&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:37&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:41&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:46&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:50&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:54&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way to read this is not by how many rolls you are going to develop, but how many rolls have already been developed. For example, if I were going to develop 5 rolls with fresh chemistry then I would start at 0. The next batch will start at 5 and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually develop batches of five 35mm rolls at a time (or the 120 equivelant) while reusing my chemicals for up to 15 rolls. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen a shift in the quality as I&amp;rsquo;ve developed more rolls through the same chemistry. I can probably use 1 quart for 20 or so rolls but I&amp;rsquo;ve never stocked up on that film that needed to be developed at once. The nightmare of scanning the film lurking around the corner is just too much for me to bare. Just keep in mind the longer you keep your chemicals and expose to air, then the weaker they become&amp;hellip; If I have chemicals sit, it will only be for a week or two in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eaOjAU&#34; title=&#34;Amber boston round chemistry bottles&#34;&gt;sealed bottle&lt;/a&gt; that is light safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pushpull&#34;&gt;Push/Pull&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not something I like doing with my color negative film. I&amp;rsquo;m typically not a fan of the look and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to develop my film in batches unless I am pushing/pulling all the film in my development container&amp;hellip; Black and white may be a different story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 56 Aug 220547 05:05:05 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about the policy, or practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Privacy Policy governs the privacy policies and practices of the Website, located at RichardSumilang.com and its sub domains. Please read the Privacy Policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;information-collected&#34;&gt;Information Collected&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Visitor, you can browse the Website to find out more about the Website. You are not required to provide any personal information as a Visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;automatically-collected-information&#34;&gt;Automatically Collected Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use the Website, we automatically collect certain computer information by the interaction of your mobile phone or web browser with our Website. Such information is typically considered non-personal information. We also collect the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cookies&#34;&gt;Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Website uses &amp;ldquo;Cookies&amp;rdquo; to identify the areas of our Website that you have visited. A Cookie is a small piece of data stored on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. We use Cookies to personalize the Content that you see on our Website. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of Cookies. However, if you disable Cookies, you may not be able to access functionality on our Website correctly or at all. We never place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;log-information&#34;&gt;Log Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information includes the name of the website from which you entered our Website, if any, as well as the name of the website to which you&amp;rsquo;re headed when you leave our website. This information also includes the IP address of your computer/proxy server that you use to access the Internet, your Internet Website provider name, web browser type, type of mobile device, and computer operating system. We use all of this information to analyze trends among our Users to help improve our Website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;information-regarding-your-data-protection-rights-under-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr&#34;&gt;Information Regarding Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information, as described in this Privacy Policy, depends on the information we collect and the specific context in which we collect it. We may process your personal information because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to perform a contract with you, such as when you use our services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have given us permission to do so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The processing is in our legitimate interests and it&amp;rsquo;s not overridden by your rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To comply with the law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to access, update or to delete the personal information we have on you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right of rectification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right of restriction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to data portability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to withdraw consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that you may be asked to verify your identity before responding to such requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-not-sell-my-personal-information-notice-for-california-consumers-under-california-consumer-privacy-act-ccpa&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Not Sell My Personal Information&amp;rdquo; Notice for California consumers under California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the CCPA, California consumers have the right to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request that a business that collects a consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data disclose the categories and specific pieces of personal data that a business has collected about consumers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request that a business delete any personal data about the consumer that a business has collected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request that a business that sells a consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data, not sell the consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;service-providers&#34;&gt;Service Providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third party companies are employed and individuals to facilitate our Website (&amp;ldquo;Service Providers&amp;rdquo;), to provide our Website on our behalf, to perform Website-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Website is used. These third-parties have access to your personal information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analytics&#34;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy &amp;amp; Terms web page: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;payments-processors&#34;&gt;Payments processors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid products and/or services on our Website are occassionally provided. In that case, a third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors) will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your payment card details will not be stored. That information is provided directly to a third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms and Conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 56 Aug 220547 05:05:05 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-overview&#34;&gt;A. Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the website RichardSumilang.com (the “Site”).  The Site is an online service owned by Richard Sumilang (or “Richard Sumilang Photography”).  Richard Sumilang has created this Site for your personal enjoyment, education and entertainment.  This Terms of Use agreement (the “Agreement”) describes the terms and conditions under which Richard Sumilang permits your use of the Site, and any other services of Richard Sumilang that display this Agreement (collectively with the Site and services, the “Services”).  This Agreement constitutes a legal agreement between you and Richard Sumilang.  Use of this Site or any of the other Services is also governed by Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s Privacy Policy, which is incorporated into this Agreement by reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By viewing, interacting with, submitting information to, or otherwise using the Services, you agree to be bound by this Agreement.  If you do not wish to be bound by this Agreement, you must not use the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify, update, or otherwise change this Agreement at any time.  By using the Services after such changes are posted, you agree to be bound by the changes. &lt;strong&gt;This Agreement was last modified on May 22nd, 2020.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;b-intellectual-property&#34;&gt;B. Intellectual Property&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All content included in this Site or in or through the other Services, such as text, photos, logos, video, graphics, sound, computer code, and the arrangement and selection of such content, is protected by copyrights, and/or other intellectual property rights of Richard Sumilang and/or third-party content providers. The business names, logos, slogans, trade dress and all other marks on this Site or in the Services are copyrights of Richard Sumilang or related third-party content providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may use material from this Site or the Services only for your own personal, non-commercial use.  No portion of this Site or the other Services may be republished, reproduced, duplicated, copied, uploaded, downloaded, posted, transmitted, modified, sold, or otherwise exploited for any purpose that is not expressly permitted by Richard Sumilang.  In the event of any permitted copying, redistribution, or publication of copyrighted material, no changes in or deletion of trademarks, author attribution or copyright notices may be made. You acknowledge that you do not acquire any ownership rights by downloading material from this Site or the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe in good faith that your copyrighted work has been reproduced on this Site or through the Services without authorization in a way that constitutes copyright infringement, please send a notice of copyright infringement containing the following information to Richard Sumilang designated copyright agent by email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of the work or material being infringed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing, including its location, with sufficient detail so that we are capable of finding it and verifying its existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact information for the notifying party (the &amp;ldquo;Notifying Party&amp;rdquo;), including name, address, telephone number, and email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A statement that the Notifying Party has a good faith belief that the material is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent or law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A statement made under penalty of perjury that the information provided in the notice is accurate and that the Notifying Party is authorized to make the complaint on behalf of the copyright owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of the copyright that has been allegedly infringed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;c-submission-of-content-by-users&#34;&gt;C. Submission of Content by Users&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain places, this Site or the Services may allow users to submit comments, blog entries, letters, ideas, photos, videos, emails or other content – either directly to the Site or the Services (including to us through the Site or the Services) or through third party service providers.  While we generally would like to permit you to provide content to or through the Site or other Services, there are certain restrictions on your providing content.  They are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License:  You retain all ownership and copyrights in the content that you submit to us.  WE WILL NOT SELL YOUR CONTENT unless you have entered into a separate contract with us allowing us to do so; but by submitting content to us, you grant Richard Sumilang the right to post it on the Site, use it as part of the Services, use it for our internal purposes, and use it to promote Richard Sumilang (the “Uses”).  More specifically, by submitting content, you agree that we have a perpetual, non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free, irrevocable, fully and freely assignable and sub-licensable license to use the content for the Uses &amp;ndash; including, but not limited to, the rights to use, display, publish, translate, reproduce, distribute, modify, prepare derivative works based upon, and perform publicly your content (or any part thereof) online and offline in any form, media or technology now known or hereafter devised for purposes of the Uses. You further agree that Richard Sumilang and its licensees have the right to use your name and likeness in connection with Richard Sumilang’ publication, display, modification, distribution or other use of such content. Richard Sumilang is free to use any ideas, techniques, inventions, concepts, know-how, or other information that you provide to Richard Sumilang (whether directly or through its third party service providers) for purposes of the Uses without compensation or remuneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards:  You agree to tag racy, sexual, graphically violent, and/ or nude content that you submit as “NSFW” or “Not Safe for Work.” Failure to do so may result in your content being removed and/or suspension of your account. You agree not to submit any content that: (a) infringes on any third-party intellectual property, publicity, privacy, moral (droit moral) or other legal rights; (b) violates any applicable law or regulation; (c) is defamatory, threatening, harassing, obscene, harmful to minors, or child pornographic; (d) is false or misleading; (e) promotes physical or emotional harm in any way; (f) contains any viruses, Trojan horses, worms or other harmful components (including, but not limited to, computer programming routines that may damage, detrimentally interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system, data or personal information); (g) is commercial in nature, other than as specifically solicited by this Site; (h) constitutes unsolicited junk or bulk email (“spam”); or (i) is tortious or criminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warranty / Indemnity:  You warrant and guarantee that you own all intellectual property, proprietary, privacy, publicity, moral (droit moral) and other rights to any content that you submit.  You further agree to defend, indemnify, and hold us harmless against: (a) any and all claims to the rights to content that you provide, (b) any and all claims that someone’s rights were violated by our display or other use of the content that you provide to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring of Content / Removal:  You agree that Richard Sumilang has no responsibility to monitor, review, edit, remove or control any content or other information that you or others submit to us and/or the Site and/or the Services.  You further agree that Richard Sumilang may, in its sole discretion, modify, remove or refuse to accept any content for any reason.  We may also decline to modify or remove content that you submitted, despite your request.  In addition, please be aware that we may not be able to modify or remove certain content, including without limitation content that has been distributed to or relied on by third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Release:  You agree that you are at least 18 years of age.  You agree to release Richard Sumilang (including without limitation, for purposes of this Section C.5 of the Agreement, the officers, directors, employees, partners, limited partners, shareholders, owners, members, affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensors, licensees, third party contractors, agents, attorneys and representatives of Richard Sumilang) from any and all liability and obligations whatsoever in connection with or arising from Ricahrd Sumilang’ use or non-use of content submitted by you or any third party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy:  Other than as set forth in the Privacy Policy, Richard Sumilang may treat any submission and/or communication between you and Richard Sumilang as non-confidential and non-proprietary.  In particular, emails, comments concerning stories, letters, blog entries, social media correspondence from you, information from sources, and similar submissions will not be considered confidential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Endorsement / Recommendation:  Richard Sumilang does not endorse, recommend, or take any responsibility for any content submitted to the Services by you or any website visitor, account holder, advertiser, service provider, vendor, or other third-party, even if Richard Sumilang displays such content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;d-disclaimer-with-respect-to-advertisers-contractors-and-other-third-parties&#34;&gt;D. Disclaimer with respect to Advertisers, Contractors, and Other Third Parties&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang specifically disclaims all responsibility for the actions or inactions of advertisers, contractors, subcontractors, Web site developers and hosts, freelancers, licensors, licensees and other third parties that may contract with Richard Sumilang or its affiliates or may otherwise provide information or services to this Site or the Services, even if such third parties provide content to or linked to this Site or the Services – including, without limitation, the providers and third party users of any blogs, forums, chat rooms, personals, classifieds, and other features of this Site or the Services that are powered or provided by third parties.  You agree that your sole course of action with respect to such third parties will be against them directly.  You further agree that you will abide by the terms of use and privacy statements, if any, that they have provided for their website or services, but that in the event of a conflict between their terms and this Agreement, this Agreement applies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;e-disclaimer-with-respect-to-other-internet-sites&#34;&gt;E. Disclaimer with respect to Other Internet Sites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang has not reviewed all of the sites, or content of sites, that may be accessed from or linked to this Site or the Services.  Ruchard Sumilang is not responsible for the content of any pages or Internet images, information, or data, which are not contained on this Site or the Services.  Viewing of any and all other Web sites shall be at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;f-prohibition-on-use--enforcement-of-terms&#34;&gt;F. Prohibition on Use / Enforcement of Terms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang may at any time, for any reason, prohibit your further use in whole or in part of this Site or the Services.  We may also take any action that we deem necessary to enforce this Agreement, and to protect against unlawful or improper use of this Site or the Services.  You hereby expressly agree to waive any and all claims you may have (whether currently in existence and/or arising hereafter) against Richard Sumilang for any failure by us to enforce this Agreement, whether against you or a third party.  Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s failure to act in a particular circumstance does not waive its right to act with respect to that circumstance or other circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;g-access-limits&#34;&gt;G. Access Limits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s express consent, you may not frame any pages from the Site or the Services, place pop-up windows over pages of the Site or the Services, or otherwise affect the display of the Site’s pages or of the Services.  Moreover, under no circumstances may you: (i) derive or attempt to derive the source or object code, source files or structure of this Site, the Services, or their content by reverse engineering, disassembly, decompilation or any other means; (ii) attempt to access the accounts of others, or attempt to penetrate security measures of the systems of Richard Sumilang or its affiliates or contractors (&amp;ldquo;hacking&amp;rdquo;), whether or not the intrusion results in corruption or loss of data; or (iii) transmit to Richard Sumilang or by means of this Site or the Services any unauthorized or unsolicited advertising, junk or bulk e-mail, or any other form of unauthorized or unsolicited transmission.  Richard Sumilang grants you permission to link to this Site (without framing it) or the Services, but may revoke this permission at any time for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain content or areas of the Site or Services may be marked “NSFW” or otherwise restricted.  You may not access that content or those areas unless you are of legal age to do so and are in compliance with any additional terms posted in association with those portions of the Site or Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;h-purchases&#34;&gt;H. Purchases&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be able to purchase video recordings, audio recordings, artwork, acrobat files, and information relating to such digital recordings, and other content (individually and collectively, “Digital Content”) and other products or services from the Site or Services. Such purchases are subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, including this &lt;strong&gt;Section H&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rights Granted:  Upon your payment of our fees for Digital Content, we grant you a perpetual, non-exclusive, non-transferable, non-sublicensable right to use the Digital Content for your personal, non-commercial, educational, or entertainment use. You may download, copy, store, transfer and burn the Digital Content only for your personal, non-commercial, educational or entertainment use. If you are unable to complete a download after payment is made, please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt; immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restrictions:  You represent, warrant and agree that you will use the Digital Content only for your personal, non-commercial, educational or entertainment use and not for any redistribution of the Digital Content or other use restricted in this &lt;strong&gt;Section H.2&lt;/strong&gt;. You agree not to infringe the rights of the Digital Content&amp;rsquo;s copyright owners and to comply with all applicable laws in your use of the Digital Content. Except as set forth in &lt;strong&gt;Section J.1&lt;/strong&gt; above, you agree that you will not redistribute, transmit, display, assign, sell, broadcast, rent, share, lend, modify, adapt, edit, license or otherwise transfer or use the Digital Content. You are not granted any synchronization, public performance, promotional use, commercial sale, resale, reproduction or distribution rights for the Digital Content. You acknowledge that the Digital Content embodies the intellectual property of a third party and is protected by law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Content and other products available through the Services are protected by federal Copyright Laws and any violation of these laws may subject the violator to civil liability and/or criminal prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risk of Loss:  You bear all risk of loss after purchase and for any loss of Digital Content you have downloaded, including any loss due to a computer or hard drive crash. We may, from time to time, remove Digital Content from the Service without notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;i--parental-control-provisions&#34;&gt;I.  Parental Control Provisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 230(d), as amended, we hereby notify you that parental control protections (such as computer hardware, software, or filtering services) are commercially available that may assist you in limiting access to material that is harmful to minors.  Information identifying current providers of such protections is available at Get Net Wise, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getnetwise.org&#34;&gt;www.getnetwise.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;j-disclaimer-of-warranties-and-limitation-of-liability&#34;&gt;J. Disclaimer of Warranties and Limitation of Liability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOUR USE OF THIS SITE AND THE OTHER SERVICES IS AT YOUR OWN RISK.  THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED ON AN &amp;ldquo;AS IS&amp;rdquo; AND &amp;ldquo;AS AVAILABLE&amp;rdquo; BASIS.  RichardSumilang.com (including without limitation, for purposes of this Section J of the Agreement, Richard Sumilang and its officers, directors, employees, shareholders, partners, limited partners, owners, members, agents, affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensors, licensees, third party contractors, attorneys and representatives and any other parties involved in creating, producing or delivering this Site, the Services or any of the content, products or services available on or through this Site or the Services) HEREBY DISCLAIMS ALL EXPRESS AND/OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, RICHARD SUMILANG MAKES NO AND DISCLAIMS ANY REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED: (i) AS TO THE OPERATION OF THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES, (ii) AS TO THE INFORMATION, CONTENT, MATERIALS, SERVICES OR PRODUCTS INCLUDED ON OR AVAILABLE THROUGH THE SITE OR THE SERVICES; (iii) THAT THE SITE OR THE SERVICES WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE; (iv) AS TO THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY, OR CURRENCY OF ANY INFORMATION, CONTENT, SERVICE, OR MERCHANDISE PROVIDED ON OR THROUGH THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES; (v) THAT THE CONTENT OF THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES DOES NOT INFRINGE ON THE RIGHTS OF YOU OR THIRD PARTIES; AND/OR (vi) THAT THE SITE, THE SERVICES, THEIR SERVERS, OR E-MAIL SENT FROM OR ON BEHALF OF RICHARDSUMILANG.COM ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICHARD SUMILANG DOES NOT GUARANTY THE CONTINUOUS, UNINTERRUPTED OR SECURE ACCESS TO THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES.  THE OPERATION OF THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES MAY BE INTERFERED WITH BY NUMEROUS FACTORS OUTSIDE THE CONTROL OF RICHARD SUMILANG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES SHALL RICHARD SUMILANG BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR OTHER DAMAGES (OTHER THAN DIRECT DAMAGES) THAT RESULT FROM THE CONTENT OF, USE OF, OR INABILITY TO USE, THIS SITE, THE SERVICES, OR ANY DIGITAL CONTENT OR OTHER MERCHANDISE OBTAINED FROM THE SITE OR SERVIES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO RELIANCE BY A USER ON ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES AND/OR DAMAGES THAT RESULT FROM MISTAKES, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS, DELETION OF FILES OR EMAIL, ERRORS, DEFECTS, VIRUSES, DELAYS IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION, OR ANY FAILURE OF PERFORMANCE, WHETHER OR NOT RESULTING FROM ACTS OF GOD, COMMUNICATIONS FAILURE, THEFT, DESTRUCTION, OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO RICHARDSUMILANG.COM RECORDS, PROGRAMS, OR SERVICES.  THIS LIMITATION APPLIES WHETHER THE ALLEGED LIABILITY IS BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, NEGLIGENCE), INFRINGEMENT, OR ANY OTHER BASIS – EVEN IF RICHARD SUMILANG HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH LIABILITY.  WITH RESPECT TO DIRECT DAMAGES, YOUR REMEDY IS LIMITED TO A MAXIMUM OF ONE HUNDRED DOLLARS ($100) AND DISCONTINUANCE OF USE OF (AND ANY MEMBERSHIP IN) THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES.  YOU HEREBY ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THIS PARAGRAPH SHALL APPLY TO ALL CONTENT, MERCHANDISE, AND/OR SERVICES AVAILABLE ON OR THROUGH THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THESE DISCLAIMERS AND LIMITATIONS APPLY TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;k-indemnification&#34;&gt;K. Indemnification&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You agree to defend, indemnify, release and hold harmless Richard Sumilang (including without limitation, for purposes of this Section K of the Agreement, RichardSumilang.com, and its officers, directors, employees, shareholders, partners, limited partners, owners, members, agents, affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensors, licensees, third party contractors, attorneys and representatives and any other parties involved in creating, producing or delivering this Site, the Services or any of the content, products or services available on or through this Site or the Services) from all liabilities, claims and expenses, including attorney’s fees and costs, that arise from, concern, or are connected with your use or misuse of this Site, the Services or any Digital Content or other merchandise that you obtain from the Site or Services.  Richard Sumilang reserves the right to assume the defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you, in which event you will cooperate with Richard Sumilang in asserting any available defenses and will pay all of RichardSumlang.com&amp;rsquo;s attorneys’ fees and costs in such defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;l-severability&#34;&gt;L. Severability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The provisions of this Agreement are intended to be severable.  If for any reason any provision of this Agreement shall be held invalid or unenforceable in whole or in part in any jurisdiction, such provision shall, as to such jurisdiction, be ineffective to the extent of such invalidity or unenforceability without in any manner affecting the validity or enforceability thereof in any other jurisdiction or the remaining provisions hereof in any jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;m-governing-law-and-jurisdiction&#34;&gt;M. Governing Law and Jurisdiction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You agree that the laws of the State of California will govern this Agreement and your use of this Site and the Services.  The state and federal courts of Los Angeles, California, shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any litigation that may arise out of, or be related to, this Agreement and/or your use of the Site or the Services.  You agree to waive any objection based on forum non conveniens or any objection to venue in Los Angeles, California, of any such action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;n-international-use&#34;&gt;N. International Use&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang makes no representation that this Site or the Services (including the content, services or products provided on or through them) are appropriate for or available to locations outside the United States of America; and using this Site or the Services from territories where it is illegal to do so is prohibited.  Any offer for a product or service through this Site or the Services is void where prohibited.  Use of this Site or the Services is done at your own risk and you are responsible for compliance with all local laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;o-assignment&#34;&gt;O. Assignment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You agree that this Agreement and all rights and licenses provided to Richard Sumilang under this Agreement are fully and freely assignable and sub-licensable by Richard Sumilang without further compensation to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;p-integration-and-modification&#34;&gt;P. Integration and Modification&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise specified herein or in a written agreement signed by Richard Sumilang, this Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between you and Richard Sumialng with respect to this Site, and supersedes all prior or contemporaneous communications or proposals between you and Richard Sumialng with respect to this Site and the Services.  You may not modify this Agreement other than by obtaining Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s signed, written consent to such a modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;q-notice--contact&#34;&gt;Q. Notice / Contact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang can be contacted at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal notices shall be sent to the following address: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;. Notice will be considered given upon receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang is entitled to assume that any address information that you provide to us is correct, and Richard Sumilang may contact you at such address. Notice to you will be considered given when sent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Emacs to 24.5</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/server/ubuntu/upgrade-emacs-to-24-5-on-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 46 Aug 5040 04:04:04 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/server/ubuntu/upgrade-emacs-to-24-5-on-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/server/ubuntu/upgrade-emacs-to-24-5-on-ubuntu-12-04/gnulogo-370x229.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dump this in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install checkinstall
mkdir -p ~/src
cd ~/src
wget https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/emacs-24.5.tar.gz
tar xf emacs-24.5.tar.gz
cd emacs-24.5
./configure
make
sudo checkinstall
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it a step further and install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syl20bnr/spacemacs&#34; title=&#34;Spacemacs&#34;&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
git clone https://github.com/syl20bnr/spacemacs ~/.emacs.d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are In-Ear Monitors?</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/in-ear-monitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 10010 01:01:01 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/in-ear-monitors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In-Ear Monitors&lt;/em&gt; (IEMs), is a type of headphone designed to be partially
inserted into a user&amp;rsquo;s ear canal by using form-fitting tips often made by a
range materials such as rubber, soft plastic, silicon, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s also
common to purchase custom molded tips to fit your ear canal. This typically
offers the best results in comfort and noise isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may notice musicians typically wearing an IEM during a live performance.
This is to listen to a custom set of instruments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other names for IEMs are In-Ear-Canalphone, canalphone, or ear-canal headphone.
People believe the acronym IEM became the popular replacement for canalphones
with the iPod generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEMs are sometimes mistakenly called earbuds. The main difference being earbuds
are worn in the opening of the ear. They are not designed to sit in the ear
canal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Page Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/programming/ruby/ror/facebook-page-analytics-ror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 126 Aug 20120 12:12:12 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/programming/ruby/ror/facebook-page-analytics-ror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to flex my programming muscle and try something new. I&amp;rsquo;ve done Ruby
for CLI tools and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/chef-gearman&#34; title=&#34;Chef-Gearman&#34;&gt;Chef cookbooks&lt;/a&gt; but never a Ruby on Rails (RoR)
application. Much of the hype with RoR is gone these days but it&amp;rsquo;s been around
long enough to be considered tested and somewhat mature like an old elitist
hipster&amp;hellip; If that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tldr;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/fb-page-analytics-ror&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Page Analytics with Ruby On Rails&#34;&gt;Just give me the source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was to create a Rails applications that provides analytics for the
last 100 Facebook posts of a Facebook page. As a user, you should be able to
login using Facebook, see a list of pages that you have authorized admin access
to, and lastly see a display of the pages&amp;rsquo; top 5 posts (out of the last 100) as
well as a sortable table of the 100 most recent posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store user and page Facebook credentials, basic Facebook profile data (name of
user, name of page, email address), and the last 100 posts in a database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each entry in the post table should include:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link to Posts (on Facebook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Message/text body of post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Shares&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Likes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Impressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date Posted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts should be sortable by number of shares, likes, comments, and date posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Top 5 Posts&amp;rdquo; display can be chosen/ranked by any arbitrary combination of
post statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-application&#34;&gt;The Application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week long into RoR land and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say it&amp;rsquo;s done&amp;hellip; Well, 98% of it is.
I was nice enough to leave a little of this project left for you to do (I
happily accept pull requests):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrieving the number of impressions for each post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app currently does not paginate to the end of all Facebook page posts. It
stops at of the first set of results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/fb-page-analytics-ror&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Page Analytics with Ruby On Rails&#34;&gt;Facebook page analytics source&lt;/a&gt; is freely made available under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&#34; title=&#34;Creative Commons License 4.0&#34;&gt;Creative Commons License v4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-system&#34;&gt;My System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby:&lt;/strong&gt; ruby 2.2.1p85 (2015-02-26 revision 49769) [x86_64-darwin14]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rails:&lt;/strong&gt; Rails 4.2.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements to run the project will be kept updated in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/fb-page-analytics-ror/blob/master/README.rdoc&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Page Analytics Readme.rdoc&#34;&gt;README.rdoc&lt;/a&gt; but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t diverge too much from this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database setup (sqlite):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;Database Setup&#34;&gt;rake db:migrate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Facebook configuration variables are externalized via environment
variables so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set these parameters:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;Configuration&#34;&gt;export FB_APP_ID=YOUR_FB_APP_ID
export FB_APP_SECRET=YOUR_FB_APP_SECRET&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/apps/register&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Register and Configure an App&#34;&gt;Read this doc&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with created a Facebook App.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two servers need to be started. The &lt;em&gt;app server&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;job server&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;Servers&#34;&gt;rails s # app server
rake jobs:work # job server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;urls&#34;&gt;Urls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application:&lt;/strong&gt; http://localhost:3000/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Web View:&lt;/strong&gt; http://localhost:3000/delayed_job/overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the graphic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/programming/ruby/ror/facebook-page-analytics-ror/db-layout-772x346.png&#34; alt=&#34;Facebook Analytics Database Graphic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application can be loaded on http://localhost:3000/. You will find a
fancy &amp;ldquo;Facebook&amp;rdquo; link in the header. Click the link and log in with the test
account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon successful log in, the system grabs all the pages the user is an
administer of and does a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the page does not exist in our db then we create it and create the
relationship between the user and the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user no longer has access to a specific page then the relationship
between the two is removed but all page data is kept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pages controller will either list all the pages a user is an admin of,
allowing the user to choose OR redirect to the stats page of the single page
they administer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stats page is then responsible for retrieving all posts. On first load,
the stats page will pull from the top of the feed all the way down. On every
subsequent request, the stats controller will pull only newer feed items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A background job is then created for each post. This background job is
responsible for fetching the likes, comments, shares, and impressions for each
post while updating the database. This background process was created so the
wait on the stats page wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly long. Because of this, you will see the
stats update on the page when you refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stats page displays a top 5 list of the most popular posts. This is
ordered by date, likes, and comments. Nothing too crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stats page then lists all posts in a table below in a sortable fashion
by clicking the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign out button will set session variables to &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt; causing an invalid
session and redirect the user to the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gems-used&#34;&gt;Gems Used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following gems were used to build the project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mkdynamic/omniauth-facebook&#34; title=&#34;OmniAuth Facebook&#34;&gt;omniauth-facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Used to handle authentication to Facebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arsduo/koala&#34; title=&#34;Koala Gem&#34;&gt;koala&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Nifty for communicating with Facebook graph API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daemons.rubyforge.org/&#34; title=&#34;Daemons Gem&#34;&gt;daemons&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Experimented with this for fun. This would be used to run
the job server in production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/collectiveidea/delayed_job_active_record&#34; title=&#34;DelayedJob ActiveRecord Backend&#34;&gt;delayed_job_active_record&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; - Used to schedule and run the background
jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ejschmitt/delayed_job_web&#34; title=&#34;Delayed Job Web&#34;&gt;delayed_job_web&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Web interface for delayed job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;refactoring&#34;&gt;Refactoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I know that can be done better off the top of my head if
this were a real world application. (I would also appreciate any feedback or
ruby-isms in the comments.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally the stats page should not be making the request to Facebook to pull
in the posts associate with the page they are on. It should be a background job
that fires up more workers to gather the metrics for each post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job worker only supports handling one post at a time. It&amp;rsquo;s fine for the
sake example but in a real world situation we should be making batch requests.
This can easily be done by passing an array of Facebook &lt;code&gt;object_ids&lt;/code&gt; to the
endpoint to eliminate multiple requests. The same could be said for the page
controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the application grows, there will be more repetition the way things were
done. I can see use for breaking some of the &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; model up by removing the
sign up code and placing it into a concern and there can be good uses for
helpers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-thoughts&#34;&gt;End Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good:&lt;/strong&gt; I was fairly impressed with the amount of work I got done in a
short amount of time without having any Ruby friends to lean on. The syntactic
sugar provided by Ruby made certain things a pleasure to work with and gems seem
well thought out with a lot of care that the Ruby community is known for. My
personal favorite being the &lt;em&gt;delayed_job_active_record&lt;/em&gt; in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also impressed by how organized Rails is. The database migration feature
was really smooth and I thought it was neat how 3rd party gems made use of that
in your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bad:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes there was too much syntactic sugar that actually did the
opposite of making code easier to read. One of my pet peeves was using hashes.
This was because the colon placement in symbols changes and sometimes there
isn&amp;rsquo;t a clear distinction where a method parameter ends and starts without
having to look very closely. I found this annoying at times because it was also
hard for my IDE (IntelliJ) to tell me what was valid code. This is more of a
Ruby dislike than RoR, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Rails side, there was also too much magic. I get it, convention over
configuration but it bit me a few times with ActiveRecord. The code didn&amp;rsquo;t error
when trying to use so it was kind of annoying to debug at times. Maybe there are
better ways to do it that I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I use RoR again? Yeah, probably. The learning curve was kind of high with
Rails but once you get in the groove of it then it&amp;rsquo;s pretty powerful with the
amount of work you can accomplish in a short amount of time. For me, this would
be great for prototyping ideas. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the great gems I found and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rails-api/rails-api&#34; title=&#34;Rails::API&#34;&gt;Rails::API&lt;/a&gt; looks pretty neat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Finest Audiophile Electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/etc/work/losslesslife/the-worlds-finest-audiophile-electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 116 Aug 15110 11:11:11 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/etc/work/losslesslife/the-worlds-finest-audiophile-electronics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to announce &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;The world&#39;s finest Audiophile Electronics. Headphones, DACs, Amplifiers, reviews, and more.&#34;&gt;LosslessLife&lt;/a&gt;, a company focusing on the best
high resolution audio gear. LosslessLife reflects the continuous hard work
and commitment in the products it believes in by creating a voice to get the
word out from the audiophile communities and to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is often assumed by the average consumer that a higher price and/or bigger
brand name results in better product. While this can be true to some degree,
consumers are often paying more for a product&amp;rsquo;s marketing expenses when
purchasing from large retail stores rather than receiving higher performing
product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strict factors such as performance, output quality, and the overall
craftsmanship of products must be met in order to make it to LosslessLife as the
company name is synonymous with the highest level of quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a market that is saturated with mediocre products, LosslessLife believes it&amp;rsquo;s
success will be by educating consumers to make smarter choices when purchasing.
We do the research for you and provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;Covering everything from high-end and audiophile headphones. Headphones and headphone amplifiers, accessories, how-to guides, and reviews.&#34;&gt;all of the facts&lt;/a&gt; in an unbiased
fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many companies sell products which they claim they would use, LosslessLife
only sells products it does use by it&amp;rsquo;s highly enthusiastic team with
backgrounds in technology, production, and an affinity for music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;stay-informed&#34;&gt;Stay informed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay connected with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;The world&#39;s finest Audiophile Electronics. Headphones, DACs, Amplifiers, reviews, and more.&#34;&gt;LosslessLife movement&lt;/a&gt; by following the latest blogs
covering everything from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;Covering everything from high-end and audiophile headphones. Headphones and headphone amplifiers, accessories, how-to guides, and reviews.&#34;&gt;high-end and audiophile headphones to amplifiers, DACs,
accessories, how-to guides, and reviews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re also on your favorite flavor of social media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/losslesslife&#34; title=&#34;Follow the audiophile gurus on Twitter @ LosslessLife&#34;&gt;Follw our Tweets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/LosslessLife&#34; title=&#34;Follow the audiophile gurus on Facebook @ LosslessLife&#34;&gt;Like us Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/losslesslife/&#34; title=&#34;Follow the audiophile gurus on Instagram @ LosslessLife&#34;&gt;Check out our snaps on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://losslesslife.tumblr.com/&#34; title=&#34;Follow the audiophile gurus on Tumblr @ LosslessLife&#34;&gt;Follow our blogs on Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-information&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the LosslessLife &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/service/mission-statement/&#34; title=&#34;An audiophile mission statement&#34;&gt;Mission Statement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/service/about-losslesslife/&#34; title=&#34;LosslessLife company information&#34;&gt;company incentives&lt;/a&gt;. Need
more? Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/service/customer-service/&#34; title=&#34;We love chatting.&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt; to LosslessLife with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Planar Magnetic Drivers?</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/planar-magnetic-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 116 Aug 10110 11:11:11 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/planar-magnetic-drivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Planar Magnetic driver, has coined a few other terms such as &amp;ldquo;orthodynamic&amp;rdquo; or
&amp;ldquo;Isodynamic&amp;rdquo;, all of which mean the same thing (in regards to headphones). They
can be described as the child of a dynamic and electrostatic driver, sort of&amp;hellip;
The best of both worlds, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/dynamic-drivers/&#34;&gt;dynamic driver&lt;/a&gt;, it requires a
magnetic field around a conductor with a current flowing thought it to drive the
diaphragm. And like the electrostatic driver, it contains a thin sheet of
flexible film. The key difference that coined the term &amp;ldquo;planar&amp;rdquo; refers to the
planar magnetic field that has a printed circuit spread across the surface of
the thin film in the same parallel plane as the diaphragm. In other words the
planar magnetic driver contains a charged flat wire or voice coil unwound on
the thin, flat film. The diaphragm is &amp;ldquo;sandwiched&amp;rdquo; with magnets on either side
of the diaphragm, and when charged the magnetic field pulls on either side of
the diaphragm pulling it one way or the other causing the air to move, creating
sound waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planar magnetic drivers are beneficial because they offer better bass response
than other headphones because of the large surface area of the membrane
producing the sound waves. Additionally, they have a wider sound range, low
distortion levels, are amplifier friendly and are more durable without loosing
their sound quality. The large surface area of the diaphragm allows the heat
generated by the currant passing through it to pass or dissipate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Dynamic Drivers?</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/dynamic-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 116 Aug 10110 11:11:11 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/dynamic-drivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;dynamic driver&lt;/em&gt;, sometimes referred to as a &amp;ldquo;moving coil&amp;rdquo; driver is the most
common driver found in headphones. It is the same technology found in speakers
around your home, but on a much smaller scale. This type of driver
consists of alternating magnetic fields powered by a tiny wire coil (or a
&amp;ldquo;voice coil&amp;rdquo;). As the current changes based on the sound playback, the coil
reacts with the magnetic field and the lightweight diaphragm rapidly compresses
and decompresses the air by pulling the diaphragm in and out from the ring
within the driver to create the sound you hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic drivers produce good bass with a decent amount of sound pressure without
the need for using excess power. Dynamic drivers are capable of producing a full
range of sound for the average listener.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are headphone drivers?</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/headphone-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 116 Aug 51145 11:11:11 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/headphone-drivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Headphones are essentially a set of tiny speakers that sit in, on or around your
ears and like all speakers, they have drivers. Everyone can agree that not all
headphones are the same or created equally. But besides the superficial
differences and the various features you may be offered such as noise cancelling
and wireless capabilities, there are other more subtle differences that can make
a huge difference. That subtle difference is determined by the type of driver
used in the headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The driver is what makes or produces the sound you hear and is the most
important part of the speaker. One can assume; the better the driver, the
better the sound, and the more powerful the output. It is the part of a speaker
that compresses and refines air to create sound waves, and the type of driver
used will dramatically impact the sound quality of a pair of headphones. The
driver unit falls in the range of 8mm to 15mm for earphones and 20mm to 50mm for
headphones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMZ Mobile Website</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 96 Aug 22090 09:09:09 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been an exciting journey from start to finish. As the head developer of
the mobile website for one of the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest blog sites, I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to
announce &lt;em&gt;Version 2&lt;/em&gt; of TMZ! Take a look at all the new features. I think you
will like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The views and opinions shared in this article are those of the author&amp;rsquo;s (Richard
Sumilang) and do not necessarily reflect TMZ, Telepictures, Warner Bros and any
staff member or affiliate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;My role&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a full time developer at TMZ. I work on TMZ products such as the desktop
site and internal applications. My current focus is bringing the technologies up
to date with modern standards while enhancing the user experience on the mobile
website. In other words, creating a brand new product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;its-more-than-just-a-pretty-face&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s more than just a pretty face&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new site provides a new fun and modern interface to interact with TMZ&amp;rsquo;s
content. It borrows designs from our native mobile applications so you feel at
home; but they have been optimized for the mobile web browsing experience. It&amp;rsquo;s
lighter, faster, and full of new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inside has been built from the ground up. While I would like to write a
series of articles detailing the various technologies I chose to build the
application, I will say ECMAScript 6 proved itself suitable as the front-end
language and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to continue upgrading the application to ECMAScript 7,
ECMAScript 8, and so fourth as JavaScript continues to gain sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;show-me-the-features&#34;&gt;Show me the features!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will notice is a fresh skin. It&amp;rsquo;s clean, intuitive, and
brings the familiarity you would expect out of a mobile website. The large
images help you find the content you are looking for while continuing to load
more articles into the feed as you scroll, keeping your browsing experience
smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/homepage.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;navigation-menu&#34;&gt;Navigation Menu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the top left we have a menu button that pulls out a panel to allow navigation
to each section of the site. Starting from the top, you can find the &amp;ldquo;Got a tip?&amp;rdquo;
button where you can submit tips directly to TMZ. Following that we have each of
our site sections in big easily clickable buttons. Below that is a &amp;ldquo;Mobile
Alerts&amp;rdquo; button allowing you to register and receive mobile alerts sent directly
to your phone. The &amp;ldquo;TV Listings&amp;rdquo; displays TMZ show listings for your area. Or if
you&amp;rsquo;re feeling like going on a tour then you can click the &amp;ldquo;TMZ Celebrity Tour&amp;rdquo;
and reserve a spot on the bus and tour hollywood. The &amp;ldquo;Login / Register&amp;rdquo; button
signs you into TMZ, allowing you to add your own comments to articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/nav-menu.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;got-a-tip&#34;&gt;Got A Tip?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling TMZ directly is still an option by clicking the &amp;ldquo;Give us a call&amp;rdquo; button.
The new section now supports sending TMZ a direct email via a web form with the
ability to upload files from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/got-a-tip.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The news contains tabs to help you sort the content in your preferred order. For
example, this feed defaults to the &lt;strong&gt;Latest&lt;/strong&gt; articles and provides you the
options of sorting by most &lt;strong&gt;Popular&lt;/strong&gt; and the most &lt;strong&gt;Commented&lt;/strong&gt; trending
results. The &lt;strong&gt;Popular&lt;/strong&gt; tab labels each article with a number for it&amp;rsquo;s
popularity. The &lt;strong&gt;Commented&lt;/strong&gt; section similarly labels each article with the
number of comments per article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/news-feed.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;article-page&#34;&gt;Article Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking an article thumbnail brings you to a beautiful view of the article that
is easy to read. The cover is either an image, video, or gallery. You can tell
what the media type is because there is either a large play button for video or
gallery icon for galleries. You can click the primary media in the cover to load
the media right away or you can scroll down the article. As you scroll you will
notice buttons for sharing an article on your social networks and the comment
count next to the article details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the article details there can be links to more related galleries, videos,
images, polls, and a number of other items (depending on what the content writer
chose to include).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the comment bubble next to the article details, or the large comment
count below the article will show load all the comments. You may log in here
using one of many social network authentications (Facebook, Twitter, Gmail, etc)
to share your thoughts. If you are already logged into the mobile website with
your TMZ account then you can comment immediately. Closing the comment page will
bring you back to the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below you will find other related articles that you may find interesting. The
want more section will display buttons to bios of celebrities mentioned in the
article and buttons to article categories that you also may find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end you will see a link to the next article from the feed you came from.
If you did not land on the article page coming from a feed then you will not see
this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/article-page.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featuring &lt;em&gt;Latest Videos&lt;/em&gt; by default, TMZ now provides access to videos by
&lt;em&gt;Category&lt;/em&gt;. Each video also has it&amp;rsquo;s own page where you can share the current
video with your social networks and find other related videos that you might be
interested in watching next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/video-latest.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;photos&#34;&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all the other feeds, bigger images and easier scrolling. The takeaway from
this section is the new thumbnail galleries that you can load by clicking on any
photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the gallery, we use larger images to take up the whole viewport of your phone
to provide a richer experience. You can swipe your thumb on a photo to easily
navigate in the direction you want to go. There are also new sharing features
per photo and more gallery suggestions when reaching the end. I think you&amp;rsquo;ll
like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/photo-galleries.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feed is similar to the latest news feed but focuses on the &lt;em&gt;Sports&lt;/em&gt;
category. You can also find sports articles while browsing other article feeds.
You will be able to easily identify a sports article by the green swipe on the
article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/tmz-sports.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;celebs&#34;&gt;Celebs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the most trending celebrity by navigating to this feed section. This section
defaults to the most &lt;strong&gt;Trending&lt;/strong&gt; celebrities and you can click on the &lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt;
tab to find a specific celebrity quicker. The &lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt; section loads smaller
thumbnails for faster scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/celebs.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;celebrity-bio&#34;&gt;Celebrity Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on a celebrity will load up a detailed biography page where you can
find more information about a celebrity. Starting from the top, you can share the
celebrity information with your social network, read their bio, find photo
galleries, videos, and/or articles featuring the current celebrity bio you are
reading. We also show related celebrities that you may be interested in
reading about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/celeb-bio.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shows&#34;&gt;Shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broken up into three sections, TMZ, TMZ Live, and TMZ Sports. You can come to
this section and watch live streaming (for TMZ Live), full episodes, and clips
for any of your favorite shows on your mobile device. You may also use the
button on the bottom of the page to find local TV listings for your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/shows.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t find what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for? Try out the new search feature. It uses an
updated backend service to provide you more accurate results than before. From
the search page you will be able to find celebrities, articles, videos, and
galleries. Celebrities will be listed first and the other page types will be
mixed in the results. You can identify each page type by the icons on the
results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/search-dave.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;try-it-out-for-yourself&#34;&gt;Try it out for yourself!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application is now live. You can access it on your mobile device by going to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tmz.com&#34;&gt;https://www.tmz.com&lt;/a&gt; or directly to &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.tmz.com&#34;&gt;https://m.tmz.com&lt;/a&gt;. This mobile website is a
huge improvement over the previous implementation and I&amp;rsquo;m proud to have my name
stamped on the face of it. Many thanks to my awesome team for help making this
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/tmz-logo.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Your OS X App Installations</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/unix-like/darwin/cask/casks-installer-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 96 Aug 20090 09:09:09 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/unix-like/darwin/cask/casks-installer-v1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I refined my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/unix-like/darwin/cask/my-cask-script/&#34; title=&#34;My Cask Script&#34;&gt;original cask script&lt;/a&gt; for installing the software needed on
multiple Mac workstations. The new version now allows you to configure parameters of
the installation such as install path and which category of applications you
wish to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this tool is to help me configure (or reconfigure) workstations as
needed by removing the manual work of finding the applications I always use
online, unpacking, and copying to applications folder. That process becomes a
tedious task when working with dozens of pieces of software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/casks-installer/fork&#34; title=&#34;Casks Installer Fork&#34;&gt;Fork it&lt;/a&gt; for your own use on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/casks-installer&#34; title=&#34;Casks Installer&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-a-sudden-update&#34;&gt;Why a sudden update?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new version of OS X El Capitan is to be released very soon. I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt
installing a fresh OS ran smoother than doing an upgrade. Maybe the scars are
that deep from the days of going Windows 95 to 98? Idk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a fresh install of El Capitan and I wanted to make sure
my apps were in order since I&amp;rsquo;ve last used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/unix-like/darwin/cask/my-cask-script/&#34; title=&#34;My Cask Script&#34;&gt;my cask script&lt;/a&gt;. The process of
manually installing each app takes longer than the actual OS install.
Furthermore, I don&amp;rsquo;t need all apps installed in one shot so I broke them up into
installable category groups&amp;hellip; Something I have been itching to do since the
original mockup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll notice a file called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/casks-installer/blob/master/install.rb&#34; title=&#34;install.rb script&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.rb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the project root. This is the
script you will interface with for installing (or uninstalling) applications.
Applications are grouped by categories located in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/casks-installer/tree/master/category&#34; title=&#34;Casks Installer Categories&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;./category&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; folder
where you can add more or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get a list of configurable options by running the &lt;code&gt;-h&lt;/code&gt; help option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ruby install.rb -h&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;options&#34;&gt;Options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;--appdir&#34;&gt;&amp;ndash;appdir&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default location cask uses for Application shortcuts is &lt;code&gt;~/Applications&lt;/code&gt;. I
change this setting in my install command to point to &lt;code&gt;/Applications&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Default:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;/Applications&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ruby install.rb --appdir=/Applications&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;--category&#34;&gt;&amp;ndash;category&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of the application category group to install (or uninstall). The category
name should reference a file in the &lt;code&gt;./category/&lt;/code&gt; directory, excluding the file
extension. If no category group is specified then all will be installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ruby install.rb --category=browsers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;or:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ruby install.rb -c browsers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;--uninstall&#34;&gt;&amp;ndash;uninstall&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This changes the default &lt;code&gt;install&lt;/code&gt; option to &lt;code&gt;uninstall&lt;/code&gt;. With this flag on you
can uninstall a category group or uninstall everything. This option requires no additional arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ruby install.rb -c browsers --uninstall&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ruby install.rb -c browsers -u&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;updates&#34;&gt;Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/casks-installer&#34; title=&#34;Casks Installer&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for updates and please add any feature
requests to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/casks-installer/issues&#34; title=&#34;Casks Installer Issues&#34;&gt;project issues&lt;/a&gt;. I welcome pull requests :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is no way to specify the specific version of an app that you
need. This hasn&amp;rsquo;t been much of an issue for me yet but I know it would be nice
to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://richardsumilang.com/&#34;&gt;Richard Sumilang&lt;/a&gt; and is
licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;
license. You are encouraged to fork this repository and make adjustments
according to your preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/88x31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bottlehead S.E.X. 2.1 Unboxed</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/bottlehead/sex/unboxed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 96 Aug 190910 09:09:09 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/bottlehead/sex/unboxed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There you have it. All the parts that I&amp;rsquo;ll be assembling for the Bottlehead
S.E.X. version 2.1. The parts in the image include the impedance switch and the
C4S components. To the far left, there is a bag I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother unraveling
because it is mainly little screws and bolts that felt easy to lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;build-order&#34;&gt;Build Order&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will do incremental builds. This way I can test the quality of a build on it&amp;rsquo;s
own before adding additional components. This is a good practice I follow in
daily software development and has proved helpful in debugging. The order will
be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S.E.X. kit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impedance switch installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C4S Upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;customizations&#34;&gt;Customizations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I dive directly into the build I will need to do a few customizations. I
figure it will be easier to do this now before the parts are assembled because
they will not be easily accessible later. The order will be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bottlehead PC-3 painting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanding and varnishing the wood frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nickeling metal components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bottlehead S.E.X. 2.1 Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/bottlehead/sex/bottlehead-sex-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 96 Aug 120947 09:09:09 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/bottlehead/sex/bottlehead-sex-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After almost a month of waiting, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bottlehead.com/?product=single-ended-experimenters-kit-2-1-for-headphones-sensitive-speakers&#34; title=&#34;Bottlhead S.E.X. kit for Headphones and Sensitive Speakers&#34;&gt;Bottlehead S.E.X.&lt;/a&gt; has finally arrived.
This will be my first of many electronic DIY projects. I will detail the journey
from start to finish. Including details like what tools I used, any problems
I encountered, and any suggestions I come up with on the way. This blog series
is sort of like an enhancement to the original guide provided with your
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bottlehead.com/?product=single-ended-experimenters-kit-2-1-for-headphones-sensitive-speakers&#34; title=&#34;Bottlhead S.E.X. kit for Headphones and Sensitive Speakers&#34;&gt;Bottlehead S.E.X.&lt;/a&gt; purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-started&#34;&gt;How it started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally I had ordered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bottlehead.com/?product=crack-otl-headphone-amplifier-kit&#34; title=&#34;Bottlehead Crack OTL Amplifier Kit&#34;&gt;Bottlehead Crack OTL Amplifier Kit&lt;/a&gt; with the
Speedball Upgrade. This amplifier is widely known as a great way to get into
audiophile DIY world and great for driving high impedance headphones like the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/1Kf3W3v&#34; title=&#34;Sennheiser HD 650 Open Back Professional Headphone&#34;&gt;Sennheiser HD 650&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s and &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/1Kf4eaH&#34; title=&#34;Sennheiser HD 800 Over-Ear Circum-Aural Dynamic Headphone&#34;&gt;Sennheiser HD 800&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s, which were the headphones
I was rocking at the time. While there are plenty of other amplifiers out in the
market, I chose to go this route for the sake of learning and building something
which seems a lot more fun than just shelling out cash on amplifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-why-did-i-switch-to-the-sex&#34;&gt;So why did I switch to the S.E.X.?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply because I like to experiment with a range of setup combinations, thus I
look for versatility in my setups. That is where the Single Ended eXperiement
comes in; or S.E.X. for short. I want the ability to use my amplifier with a wide
range of headphones and power desktop speakers. The S.E.X. has an output
impedance upgrade option that makes this easily possible. The S.E.X. defaults to
your speakers when there isn&amp;rsquo;t a pair of headphones plugged into the jack. While
I&amp;rsquo;m going all out, why not upgrade to the C4S load boards, right? Makes sense to
me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-beauty-of-it&#34;&gt;The beauty of it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest benefits of DIY besides a fun project and learning, is the
ability to customize everything to your liking. My amplifier at the end will not
look like the stock Bottlehead S.E.X. pictures. This journey will include,
varnishing, painting, and a custom nickeling job for a sweet hot rod look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be posting a progress updates approximately once a week. As with
everything else on this blog, we&amp;rsquo;re here to learn and experiment. There might be
errors or perhaps some better way to do things. I would love to hear any
questions or suggestions in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
