<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Sumilang</title>
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 26 Aug 100245 02:02:02 PST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Roon On NAS
          
            - Restrict directory access on Synology
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/apps/synology/roon-on-nas-synology-restricted-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 100245 02:02:02 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/apps/synology/roon-on-nas-synology-restricted-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run your own Synology NAS, you may want to run roon directly on your server for audio streaming. &lt;a href=&#34;https://roononnas.org/&#34; title=&#34;Roon On Nas&#34;&gt;Roon on Nas&lt;/a&gt; provides a package to conveniently install on your Synology server. The issue with this option is that the Synology service runs without any restriction on what it can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed this issue when configuring my client. While adding the location of my music, the roon client was able to browse the entire NAS. Though the roon app will only add music to its library, this was not something I wanted available to any roon client that was on my network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-solution&#34;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using docker we can create a container to run the roon server and give the container access only to our music directory via a mount. Essentially making this a jailed environment. A roon client will still have the ability to browse the whole system the server is running on, but now the system is the container whose files don&amp;rsquo;t mean much to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steef de Bruijn was kind enough to provide a &lt;a href=&#34;https://roononnas.org/&#34; title=&#34;Roon On Nas&#34;&gt;dockerfile&lt;/a&gt; for running the latest roon server. Here&amp;rsquo;s my setup process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;em&gt;Docker&lt;/em&gt; app your NAS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Registy&lt;/em&gt; tab and enter &lt;code&gt;roonserver&lt;/code&gt; in the search field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the &lt;code&gt;steefdebruijn/docker-roonserver&lt;/code&gt;, click it, then click &lt;em&gt;Download&lt;/em&gt;. Choose the &lt;code&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt; tab, find &lt;code&gt;steefdebruijn/docker-roonserver:latest&lt;/code&gt; and click &lt;em&gt;Launch&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container name: &lt;em&gt;Whatever you want to call the server&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Advanced Settings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Volume&lt;/em&gt; tab and add the following folders.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folder: &lt;code&gt;/path/to/data&lt;/code&gt; (eg: &lt;code&gt;/roon/data&lt;/code&gt;), Mount Path: &lt;code&gt;/data&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folder: &lt;code&gt;/path/to/backup&lt;/code&gt; (eg: &lt;code&gt;/roon/backup&lt;/code&gt;), Mount Path: &lt;code&gt;/backup&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folder: &lt;code&gt;/path/to/app&lt;/code&gt; (eg: &lt;code&gt;/roon/app&lt;/code&gt;), Mount Path: &lt;code&gt;/app&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folder: &lt;code&gt;/path/to/music&lt;/code&gt; (eg: &lt;code&gt;/roon/music&lt;/code&gt;), Mount Path: &lt;code&gt;/music&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Network&lt;/em&gt; tab and check &lt;em&gt;Use the same network as Docker host&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Environment&lt;/em&gt; tab and &lt;em&gt;Add&lt;/em&gt; your &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_tz_database_time_zones&#34; title=&#34;List of tz database time zones&#34;&gt;time zone&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eg: &lt;em&gt;variable&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;TZ&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;America/Los Angeles&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Apply&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Next&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Done&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to see your new container running momentarily under the &lt;em&gt;Container&lt;/em&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing to do is fire up your roon client on a device and the music directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open roon client on your device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the pullout menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Storage&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Add folder&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the mount path you specified on your docker container for music (eg: &lt;code&gt;/music&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should notice that you are browsing only the contents of your container and not all the shares on your Synology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wala!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Astell &amp; Kern SP2000T Review
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/astell-and-kern/sp2000t-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 220145 01:01:01 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/astell-and-kern/sp2000t-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The search for the perfect DAP continues! This journey began with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/astell-and-kern/sr25-mkii-review/&#34;&gt;A&amp;amp;K SR25 MKII&lt;/a&gt; and I suggest giving that a read first as this is part of a series and referenced at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering how I started at $750 DAP then jumped over 3x time the prices to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/367yKva&#34; title=&#34;Astell &amp;amp; Kern A&amp;amp;Ultima SP2000T Hi-Res Portable Player&#34;&gt;$2,500 DAP&lt;/a&gt;. I won&amp;rsquo;t lie, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t an easy pill to swallow but with enough time and effort, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably able to rationalize anything. When I took another look at the products out there, A&amp;amp;K still made the most the sense to me. I really like their locked in Android UI and what their DAPs have to offer. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3H5uusS&#34; title=&#34;Astell &amp;amp; Kern SA700 Portable Music Player (Vegas Gold)&#34;&gt;SA700&lt;/a&gt; in vegas gold really captured my attention for the next purchase. Unfortunately I found enough negative critisms for me to pass it up. If I was going to be paying so much for a DAP, at this point I figured I should look at whats the latest and greatest, and what has the most interesting features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/367yKva&#34; title=&#34;Astell &amp;amp; Kern A&amp;amp;Ultima SP2000T Hi-Res Portable Player&#34;&gt;SP2000T&lt;/a&gt; stood out from the rest of the lineup. I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of a DAP with both vacuum tube and transistor amps built in. Not only did it let you select between tube or OP amp, it let you combine the two for for a warm yet accurate sound&amp;hellip; Well, at least according to the marketing material. At any rate, this was a technological masterpiece that was should be worth it&amp;rsquo;s asking price. Lets dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-quality&#34;&gt;Build Quality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the SR25 MKII in the previous review, the build quality was great. No better or worst. I did appreciate how most of the back was metal. I feared it might affect the bluetooth or wifi, but to my surprise it didn&amp;rsquo;t. A matter of fact, the 802.11 a/b/g/n/ac (2.4/5GHz) support really helped! I have an older wifi system and this device had better connectivity versus the SR25 MKII. The firmware update was quick and noticeably faster at downloading too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aesthetics&#34;&gt;Aesthetics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The larger screen is definitely nice. It still doesn&amp;rsquo;t take up the whole area you think it should, but I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get used to it. The SR25 had the angled screen as it&amp;rsquo;s gimmick and for this device I&amp;rsquo;d say its the colored LED light on the rear. It makes it seem kinda cool initially, kinda borg-ish, kinda daft punk. It changes colors depending on quality of file you&amp;rsquo;re playing. I already forgot what meant a low quality file (maybe red?) but I did feel like keeping notes of those files as a reminder to re-rip that media into higher quality. However being that the light was on the back, it became useless fast unless you are the type of person who puts your DAPs face down while in use. I think they nailed that feature just right on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3H5uusS&#34; title=&#34;Astell &amp;amp; Kern SA700 Portable Music Player (Vegas Gold)&#34;&gt;SA700&lt;/a&gt; with having the light on the volume knob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ergonomics&#34;&gt;Ergonomics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever held a thin brick in your hands? Thats what this was like. The large screen was a joy to use but the physical buttons are still poor. The power button is moved to the top of this device so its less accident prone than the SR25 but not really because you know if you target the top corner of your SR25 buttons then you&amp;rsquo;ll hit the power button. It still suffers from not knowing exactly what the buttons are on the left and no hold button. Maybe this gigantic device is not really meant for pockets? It almost feels like it. And unless you have basketball player hands, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably not be operating this device with one hand. The volume knob is a little short compared to the SR25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accessories&#34;&gt;Accessories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll get the screen protectors out of the box which is nice. (I skipped adding them on this time around due to the bubble issue I previously had on the SR25.) It comes with a nice colored leather case that actually feels like real leather. The fit on this isn&amp;rsquo;t so great though. It&amp;rsquo;ll sit snuggly in the case but the problem with the awkward shapes A&amp;amp;K uses is making the leather case wrap around it like a glove. You&amp;rsquo;ll get air pockets (for lack of a better description) on the flap that covers the left buttons. Imagine pressing down on the leather through some air to hopefully feel the location of the button. Forget about any tactile feedback trying to find the button locations. The volume knob being a little short fits in the case awkwardly as well. Actually I&amp;rsquo;m really starting to think that their futuristic designs do more harm than good for products that should be handheld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the package your DAP will come in a nice wood box. As a hobbyist woodworker, I really appreciated this and it ads to feeling of top quality product. I wish other manufacturers would take note of this level of packaging&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you Leica M11 :-P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-interface-and-software&#34;&gt;User Interface and Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to add about the user interface experience from what I&amp;rsquo;ve already said in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/astell-and-kern/sr25-mkii-review/&#34;&gt;SR25 MKII review&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s basically the same thing with the expception of the ability to control how much tube vs op amp power you want. That aside, I have a huge bone to pick with the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When receiving the device, I had 650gb of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3sOcIpb&#34; title=&#34;SanDisk 1TB Extreme microSDXC UHS-I Memory Card with Adapter&#34;&gt;1tb microSD&lt;/a&gt; ready to go. It was the same one used in my SR25 MKII. I popped it in and it couldn&amp;rsquo;t read any of the files. Actually, I noticed the files went hidden during my time with the SR25 MKII. I tried turning on hidden files and folders, searching through the command line, and nada&amp;hellip; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything on the disk. But I did notice the space being used and the amount of space free was right in my disk utility app. I figured this was some weird thing that maybe A&amp;amp;K does for who knows what reason. I thought it would be ok so long as the SP2000T would be able to see the files, but it couldn&amp;rsquo;t. So after some time tinkering with it, I figure I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to reformat the card and put my music on back on it all over again. If you know how time consuming it is to put that much data back on a card, then you know my pain&amp;hellip; (Yeah I know, first world problems&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bummer hear was I was not able to start enjoying my music right away. The device sat in it&amp;rsquo;s lonesome while I had to reformat and transfer music back onto the card. I was in the honeymoon phase with the device and I thought we&amp;rsquo;d be together forever, so I took my time and decided to transfer 1tb of music onto my card so we really could get to know eachother through the burn in period. Lets talk about that for a minute&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried transfering the music first from my NAS over wifi. NAS to desktop, then USB-C to device memory card loaded. I noticed my wifi transfered the files over about 25% faster (not scientifically measured, just guessing) to my machine across the house than I could copy the files over USB-C to the device. No worries though, I had only planned to do this once&amp;hellip; Until it failed. Android file transfer crashed after many hours of file transfering to the device. I found out that Android File Transfer is really sensitive to certain characters in a filename. This is super frustrating as I had to find the filename that I thought was the culprit, rename it, and resume multiple times. To top it off, it&amp;rsquo;s not even super crazy file names! I cant remember all of the characters that would make it flip out but they were silly things like question marks, not super fancy foreign characters in greek or chinese. After losing about another day in doing this I gave up and ordered a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3LHYP4n&#34; title=&#34;Vanja Micro USB OTG Adapter and USB 2.0 Portable Memory Card Reader for SD-3C SDXC SDHC MMC RS-MMC Micro SDXC Micro SD Micro SDHC Card and UHS-I Cards&#34;&gt;USB-C micro sd memory card reader&lt;/a&gt; and waited for that to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I had this DAP I wanted to enjoy and I heard reviewers gloss over it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://roonlabs.com/r/6WI8gmmISkeett3RXP3wSA&#34; title=&#34;Roon Labs&#34;&gt;roon&lt;/a&gt; support. I decided to look into this with the downtime and became a huge roon lover! Imagine if spotify and tidal had a mutant baby that focused on your local music library and that&amp;rsquo;s sorta what roon is. It&amp;rsquo;s kind&amp;rsquo;ve a spotify way to enjoy your music library with the best equalization support I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the market. It has new ways to rediscover your music and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to really explain why its awesome without taking over this review. But anyways, I was able to play music from my roon library straight onto the SP2000t. This was &lt;em&gt;super cool&lt;/em&gt; as there is no way I could ever have my full library on a DAP. The device being &lt;em&gt;roon ready&lt;/em&gt; basically means its seen on your network as a roon output source. Your DAP will have basic controls like play/pause and I think rewind/next IIRC, but thats it. You will have to interface with roon through another device where you can install a roon client. This allowd me to enjoy my music until the SD card reader was delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A day or two later the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3LHYP4n&#34; title=&#34;Vanja Micro USB OTG Adapter and USB 2.0 Portable Memory Card Reader for SD-3C SDXC SDHC MMC RS-MMC Micro SDXC Micro SD Micro SDHC Card and UHS-I Cards&#34;&gt;micro sd card reader&lt;/a&gt; arrives. Just to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m doing things as right as possible, I format the card with the SP2000T instead of my computer. I take out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3sOcIpb&#34; title=&#34;SanDisk 1TB Extreme microSDXC UHS-I Memory Card with Adapter&#34;&gt;card&lt;/a&gt;, pop it into the reader, and stick it directly into my NAS. I begin the process of copying about ~1tb of music over and this process is going to cost me another day to complete. No worries, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling pretty certain this will be the last time I have to do this. I keep an eye on the card and just about 24 hours later it&amp;rsquo;s ready! Hooray and a big &lt;strong&gt;FU&lt;/strong&gt; to Android File Transfer :) Filled with excitement, I slide in the SD card into it&amp;rsquo;s slot and the SP2000T starts doing it&amp;rsquo;s scan. I smile, I think it smiles back at me, and the background scan of music starts to proceed. That&amp;rsquo;s great, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have time for that. I pull open the menu and navigate to SD card storage and before I can select where to go, the device restarts&amp;hellip; Ok don&amp;rsquo;t freak out, maybe it was just too much for the SP2000T to handle all at once? The process happens again and again and again until I take out the SD card. Darn it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not good. Honeymoon phase is now quickly wearing off and I reach out to customer support. The best they could tell me is that I must have a corrupt file on my card or maybe my card was corrupt? I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe my new card could be corrupt so quick that was just purchased a month ago for the SR25. Anything is possible though. I ran disk diagnostics on it and no errors came back. I started with the lowest hanging fruit of just reformatting the card and copying the files over again rather than trying to figure out which of my 1tb worth of files might be corrupt. Here&amp;rsquo;s to another day of playing the waiting game, but this time I copy a different set up files that added up to 1tb. Once the card was ready, I popped it back in her and again! She seizured and restart during the scan. Oh boy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reach back to customer support and ask if there is anyway they could tell help me pinpoint the perhaps corrupt file? They suggested maybe only having files that the device supported such as &amp;ldquo;WAV, FLAC, WMA, MP3, OGG, APE, AAC, ALAC, AIFF, DFF, DSF, MQA&amp;rdquo; (from their email) and not anything else such as &amp;ldquo;.JPG, .PDF., Apple Playlist File, .ITL, .M4A, &amp;hellip;etc&amp;rdquo;. I thougt this was an interesting list they gave as I know I definitely had jpegs, cues, and text files on my SR25 which didn&amp;rsquo;t cause it crash. I also know my library is mostly FLAC and only maybe 0.1% MP3 files. Whatever, I&amp;rsquo;ll play along. I put together a little command to remove everything that didn&amp;rsquo;t match their criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I ran the command in my sd card path where my music for my DAP is located. Kiss your files goodbye if you accidentally run it in the wrong place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;a&amp;k-supported-files-only.sh&#34;&gt;find . -type f -not \( -iname &#39;*.wav&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.flac&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.wma&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.mp3&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.ogg&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.ape&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.aac&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.alac&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.dff&#39; \
-or -iname &#39;*.mqa&#39; \
\) -print0 | xargs -0  -I {} rm -v {}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had little faith in this working and of course it didn&amp;rsquo;t help. Device is still restarting. Crap. Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to figure out how to scrub my library for corrupt files to get this thing working. Eventually I talked myself into doing this because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t many other options. And I figured having a clean music library must be like having good hygiene. I spent more time trying to figure out how to do this. I was so over it that I was even willing to pay for an app to just take care of it if it would mean I could get on with my life. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything suitable and fixing it via scripts was the way to go again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My process ended up kind&amp;rsquo;ve simple, though manual. I focused on my FLACs since my MP3 collection is miniscule. First I needed a list of corrupt files and a command to fix them. So here we go&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This command will check all your flac files in the current path and write the output to a file called &lt;code&gt;flac-report.txt&lt;/code&gt; on your desktop. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it does not delete or alter anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;flac-corrupt-files.sh&#34;&gt;find . -type f \( -name &#39;*.flac&#39; \) -not -path &#39;*/.*&#39; -print0 | xargs -0 -I {} flac -t {} 2&gt;&amp;1 | tee ~/Desktop/flac-report.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skim through the text file and search for any corrupt keywords. The main thing the &lt;code&gt;flac&lt;/code&gt; test command scans for are files that don&amp;rsquo;t have a md5 hash that matches their track info. To my surprise, I only found 12 files with issues. I was pretty excited at this point because I figured this surely had to be the culprit. They were all in my &lt;em&gt;classical&lt;/em&gt; directory which was pretty high up in the alphabetical hierachy of files. I figured the DAP would probably scan in alphabetical order so this would explain why it crashes so quick during the scan. (FYI - It never gave me enough time to browse my files before restarting.) Luckily for me, there were just a few directories that contained the corrupt files so I created a little loop to go through all the files in a directory and fix them all instead writing a command per file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This command will loop through &lt;code&gt;.flac&lt;/code&gt; files and create a fixed version of the file in a relative directory called &lt;code&gt;fixed&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;flac-repair-files.sh&#34;&gt;for file in *.flac
do
  flac --verify --decode-through-errors --preserve-modtime -o fixed/$file $file
done
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I retested the new files and they were good according to &lt;code&gt;flac -t&lt;/code&gt;. So I replaced the originals with the fixed and with a tired smile on my face, I slid that sd card back into the DAP. I thought I could see the finish line, but it was a mirage. The DAP continued to crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absolute last thing I could do is another thing what A&amp;amp;K customer support suggested. Copy over smaller batches of files to find the problematic ones. I started this process and it was slow and brutal. (Especially with the amount of files I wanted on my DAP.) I figured out a little trick to make it a little less painful than slowly transfering all the files over again. The A&amp;amp;K DAPs treats files/directories with a &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; dot in front of them (eg: &lt;code&gt;.classical&lt;/code&gt;) as a hidden file and will not scan them. This might be valuable to you if youwant to narrow it down this way. Though its quicker, but still requires removing the SD card from the DAP and adding the dot through your computer as a mounted drive. You can&amp;rsquo;t keep your card in the device the whole time and do it through Android File Transfer&amp;hellip; Yeah I know, that sucks :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far you might be wondering how I finally got it working? Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I started the process of manually narrowing down the files and threw in the towel. At $2,500 this thing should&amp;rsquo;ve been made much better. I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have spent weeks trying to get figure out why this device is throwing tantrums. (It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that I was also coming from a failed experience with the SR25 MKII.) I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer myself and as a basic principle, software should be designed to fail gracefully. A&amp;amp;K totally missed this on their device. What this means is that an error shouldn&amp;rsquo;t bring the whole system to its knees. The era of bluescreens of death should&amp;rsquo;ve been left with Windows 95. For example, if the scanning of files found a file it couldn&amp;rsquo;t read due to (insert whatever reason here), then just ignore the file and safely move on. I could live with the device not being able to play a song. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen players before that try to play a corrupt file and just skip to the end or next track. That experience is totally acceptable. You can even go further and enable and &lt;em&gt;debug&lt;/em&gt; mode that can write a log to the device where we can see errors. I&amp;rsquo;ve went ahead and suggested this to their customer support team and might give their devices a try again in the future if they do this. Otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;m sad to say this relationship with A&amp;amp;K is over. I have no interest in going to the SP2000 and wasting more time debugging their players. This experience sadly left me feeling pretty low about DAPs because I thought A&amp;amp;K was around the top of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to end the article with bad taste in my mouth so lets talk about a few things they got right&amp;hellip; If you&amp;rsquo;re still here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-features&#34;&gt;Modern Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://roonlabs.com/r/6WI8gmmISkeett3RXP3wSA&#34; title=&#34;Roon Labs&#34;&gt;roon&lt;/a&gt; earlier and if this device made me love one thing, it was definitely roon! If you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried it out, seriously go check it out. Don&amp;rsquo;t make the mistake of thinking of it as a replacement for how you listen to your music, but instead think of it as just another way to rediscover your music. But, ahem, getting back on track&amp;hellip; The BT experience was nearly the same as the SR25 MKII. It was annoying to connect to the car as it had the same weird process of going BT Sinc then back to BT for an inital connection. It did not connect to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/34BMjCE&#34; title=&#34;Denon PMA-150H Integrated Network Amplifier&#34;&gt;Denon PMA-150H&lt;/a&gt;. The BT Sinc feature was still poor with my phone, but it did connect well to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3HMJgG8&#34; title=&#34;Klipsch The Sixes Powered Monitor&#34;&gt;Klipsch - The Sixes Powered Monitors&lt;/a&gt;. I was finally able to walk around my room with a solid connection to the speakers which was a breath of fresh air. The WiFi connectivity (802.11 a/b/g/n/ac 2.5/5ghz) really made a difference too. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect much from the SR25 but this put it to shame which I found really important if you&amp;rsquo;re into streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot about the hybrid amp support. On paper this sounds real cool. In my  experience with the device, I heard no difference. Perhaps there is some sort of burn in time but I thought going from completely Tube AMP mode to completely OP mode would&amp;rsquo;ve made a clear difference. Maybe my ears aren&amp;rsquo;t tuned enough but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t here any difference worth noting and I don&amp;rsquo;t think burn in should matter since the two AMP sources are completely different. It makes no sense for them to start off sounding exactly the same and grow apart with burn in right? Oh, here I got again dropping negatives&amp;hellip; So much for a positive ending heh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;customer-support&#34;&gt;Customer Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They remained responsive but were only able to provide very limited high level support. They were willing to replace the unit but after months of fiddling with 4 of their units in total, I was no longer interested. At this point I was ready to apply for a QA position at their company (j/k). But really, they are nice people and I think like they almost have something solid. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m am an isolated incident. I must be since they seem to be successful? I want to believe thats what it is but I cannot pretend my incidents didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. I want them to succeed and I hope they take what I&amp;rsquo;ve written here seriously. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind trying out their products again in the future or if they want to work together on it. For now, this device is going back and the search for the perfect DAP continues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Astell &amp; Kern SR25 MKII Review
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/astell-and-kern/sr25-mkii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 126 Aug 271245 12:12:12 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/astell-and-kern/sr25-mkii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set out looking for my first DAP. I tend to look for the highest quality before the law of diminishing returns takes into too great of an affect. To me, this is the point where paying more only gives you a fraction more performance. Some would argue that&amp;rsquo;s where the magic is in audio equipment. (I&amp;rsquo;ll table that for another write-up.) Along with my bag of requirements are a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aesthetics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ergonmics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Interface and Software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modern features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this search I found the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36ac5P0&#34; title=&#34;Astell&amp;amp;Kern A&amp;amp;Norma SR25 Portable High Resolution Audio Player&#34;&gt;Astell &amp;amp; Kern SR25&lt;/a&gt;. An absolutely beautiful device that seemed to check all the boxes. It was about the perfect size to be portable on walks. The system was android but it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a phone with a headphone jack. It felt like a device whose sole purpose was music. While researching the device, I found out the mk2 version was only a couple of weeks from being launched so I put my money towards that and waited. I was excited to have this new toy in time for the winter vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-quality&#34;&gt;Build Quality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build quality is probably almost as good as it gets. Its feels like solid aluminum, the screen is nice and bright, and has a fingerprint magnet glass back like you would find on any cell phone these days. The buttons are clicky and tactile feeling. The volume knob is also positioned nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aesthetics&#34;&gt;Aesthetics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all A&amp;amp;K devices, they look like something out of the future. It&amp;rsquo;s left leaning screen is suppose to make it more ergnonimc but I found that to be more gimmicky than anything. The screen doesn&amp;rsquo;t fill the whole face of the device as it looks like it should. It feels like you get ripped off a bit at first. Because of this, I didn&amp;rsquo;t order a black case. I opted for the orange to have some contrast against that area. More on that in the &lt;em&gt;Accessories&lt;/em&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ergonmics&#34;&gt;Ergonmics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging by gloves I wear and tool handles I buy, I have regular medium sized hands which makes this device fit perfectly in the hand. The buttons feel like they are all in the right place for ease of use but most times I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m clicking. There are four buttons on the left hand side, with the top button having minor shape difference. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to feel the difference but you just know the top button is power. I can never remember the what the 3 identical buttons underneath do. One is for forward and rewind obviously and I guess the one under power is for pause? I find myself having to think way too much about which button I&amp;rsquo;m trying to press so that I don&amp;rsquo;t press the wrong one and most times end up having to look at the device. And even then, since there are no labels on the buttons I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which button does what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up with Walkmans, I found the hold button essential. 10/10 times I would accidentally click a button that would change the track I was listening to or rewind it when pulling it out of my pocket no matter how careful I was. This was a bit of a bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volume knob was an interesting guy. Each turn adjusts the volume so little that you may not notice you accidentally hit it up or down. I used this device with my Sennheiser HD 800 S and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3LxTfBk&#34; title=&#34;Shure SE846&#34;&gt;Shure SE846&lt;/a&gt; IEMs. I found myself having to use the volume knob to get the volume level on the screen then using the screen to dial in the volume I wanted. This two steps to set the volume wasn&amp;rsquo;t so great. I feel like having real buttons should allow you to bypass the screen entirely. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re the type that enjoys dialing in your volume so precisely, then maybe this is what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the sharp edges of the design of the unit are actually quite sharp. I was hoping this could be a device I could use without a case but unfortunately not. The device will slip around with it&amp;rsquo;s glass back and probably scratch easily while holding it will be scratching your hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accessories&#34;&gt;Accessories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box you get a screen protector for the front and the glass back. They were decent but for the life of me I couldn&amp;rsquo;t a bubble out of the front screen. Heh. The screen protectors film is also held on by a sticker that leaves residue on it when peeled off. I found that quite annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3I3bTPL&#34; title=&#34;Astell&amp;amp;Kern A&amp;amp;Norma SR25 MKII Case&#34;&gt;case&lt;/a&gt; is necessary if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel the sharp edges each time you hold the device. The cases fit very nice and tight. This is a very good thing but you&amp;rsquo;ll lose access to your SD card slot if you prefer loading your media by directly connecting your SD card slot to your computer. Otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll be stuck with Android File Transfer which will be a nightmare when you have somewhat special characters in your song names. If you actually found side the buttons useful before using a case, then forget about it with a case. Finding the buttons by touch is completely gone (except for the volume) which turns the device to a screen only device&amp;hellip; Except of course when you pull it out of your pocket, at which point you still might accidentally click a button&amp;hellip; but I did find it happened less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the case material is actually real leather, but it feels coated with a weird sheen that gives the touch a bit of a plastic sense. I ordered the orange color in the hopes it would come a bit more like a naked leather tan color but it came as orange as its pictured on the site. I know this is purely subjective, but I tried to like it and thought it would grow on me but it never did. It just feels and looks cheap. I think all the original SR25 case color options were much better. Unfortunately they are not compatible unless you feel like doing minor modifications to them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-interface-and-software&#34;&gt;User Interface and Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is one thing I think they got right, mostly. While searching for my first DAP, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want something that looked like an Android phone home screen with a web browser and bunch of Google play store junk on it. (Basically a phone with a headphone jack.) When I search for a tool, I&amp;rsquo;m generally looking for something that does one thing good, instead of a bunch of things mediocrely. Swiss army knifes have their place. I like the idea of having a DAP that is not loaded with a bunch of personal apps from the Play Store that may have sensitive information. If I did that, then my DAP would require a password to log in. I never had that on any of my walkmans growing up so why start now? You can also load things like Tidal and Spotify onto the DAP without using the Google Play Store through the A&amp;amp;K interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My idea of a DAP is a device I can take on walks with me, use in my workshop, or take on camping trips with me while being off the grid. When I set my DAP down, I like anyone to go ahead and browse the tracks or change them without worrying what sensitive data is on there should it get lost and fall into the wrong hands. This is the point of keeping my phone close to me, and the DAP accessible. And thats exactly what happened happened in my last RV trip. Different people controlled the music at different times throughout the trip and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to explain how to use or what to do. It was simple and intuitive. They just picked it up and played whatever genre or artist they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equalizer is by far the most customizable I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced on a DAP. (Take that with a grain of salt.) Almost all the options you need to dial in your settings perfectly. This was actually a lot better than what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in pricier DAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a weird thing with album covers as well. Naturally I expect an album cover to display on the DAP screen for the current media playing if it has one. Oddly, when playing over bluetooth to my car I will sometimes see the album art on my car&amp;rsquo;s display and not on the DAP. There is definitely some inconsistencies going on there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to nitpick on one thing, it would be the floating back button. I removed it as it gets in the way a bit but I found it troublesome to go back at times when I was a on a streaming service. It seem to be missing at times when it was needed, but if you&amp;rsquo;re on the normal A&amp;amp;K player software then I don&amp;rsquo;t think its generally needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-features&#34;&gt;Modern Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have the obvious things such as 4.4mm headphone jack, USB-C, micro SD card slot, probably roon (spoiler alert: I&amp;rsquo;ll be reviewing that in my SP2000t article), and bluetooth (BT). Well, sorta bluetooth. This is where the device falls apart for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audiophiles will say that BT is not Hi-res, even through LDAC and I completely agree. However, my expectation for a $750 (USD) mp3 player&amp;hellip; Sorry, I mean DAP, is to have working BT. Let me explain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this is a portable &amp;ldquo;mp3 player&amp;rdquo; in 2021. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to talk it down, but it is what it is. BT is a ~25 year old technology and when I see it on a product spec sheet from a high end manufacturer, I expect it to just work. There should be no question about it especially if the product is advertising features of &amp;ldquo;Wireless Hi-Fi Sound Through BT Sink&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll start there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BT Sink sounds like a nice feature. It basically turns your DAP into a BT receiver. This is really nice as it now allows you to use all your wired headphones/iems as BT devices. This is incredibly useful in an age where phones and tablets no longer come with headphone jacks (thanks Apple!). The issue is, it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well. I could have my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36bKvkp&#34; title=&#34;Unlocked Google Pixel 5&#34;&gt;Google Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; placed literally right next to the device and have constant dropouts and static. I tried the same thing with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3LypZuk&#34; title=&#34;2021 Apple 11-inch iPad Pro&#34;&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; and the results were actually a lot better so long as you keep the DAP around ~3ft from the iPad. Any further and be ready to welcome static and dropouts. I tried this feature on a casual walk as well. I used my phone to broadcast music to my DAP which were in separate pants pockets and, well, fuhgeddaboudit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on my things to try out was using the device to stream to my car&amp;rsquo;s stereo system (Tesla Model X). This requires a special song and dance just to get it connected. After a bunch of trial and error, I figured out the special sequence that must happen to connect the device. First you must turn on BT Sink on the DAP to allow the vehicle to find the device as it won&amp;rsquo;t work the other way around. I know this is weird because I don&amp;rsquo;t want play music from the car to my DAP but please follow along. After this connection is made, there is a trust between both systems. You can then turn off BT Sink and enable regular BT. The vehicle should see the device and you can now play music from your DAP. However, should you momentarily connect your phone back to your vehicle then expect to do the whole song and dance each time when you want to reconnect your DAP to your vehicle. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why this is as this is definitely not the pairing sequence I&amp;rsquo;ve had to do with many other Android phones I owned in the past. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely annoying though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving along, I decided to try playing music through my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/34BMjCE&#34; title=&#34;Denon PMA-150H Integrated Network Amplifier&#34;&gt;Denon PMA-150H Integrated Network Amplifier&lt;/a&gt;. I figured this could be nifty as the UI on the SR25 mk2 is much more convenient than that on Denon. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried every which way to connect the two and the DAP simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t see it. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any issues connecting my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36bKvkp&#34; title=&#34;Unlocked Google Pixel 5&#34;&gt;Android phone&lt;/a&gt; to the denon so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the issue could be. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I have a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3HMJgG8&#34; title=&#34;Klipsch The Sixes Powered Monitor&#34;&gt;Klipsch - The sixes powed speakers&lt;/a&gt; in a bedroom. They are able to make a connection fine but I have to keep the DAP right next to the speakers in order for it to maintain a connection. Any slight movement of device and you&amp;rsquo;ll experience static. Forget about having the device next to you if you want to control the music from another part of a room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and I almost forgot, I did take the device camping with me. I rented an RV for a family trip which was equipped with a Pioneer AVR-220EX system. It did connect to the device fine but again there was static while trying to listen to music while driving. When we reached our campsite I thought it would be fine once we were stationary. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t. The device had to be left on top of the dashboard for a somewhat ok connection. If I tried to use the device anywhere else in the RV then fuhgeddaboudit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;customer-support&#34;&gt;Customer Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe the BT support could be so poor on such a premium product. I wrote to customer support and explained all this. They believed this be odd as well. They were fairly quick with their email responses and issued me out a replacement in a timely manner. Kudos to them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received the second device (brand new) and it came with unfortunately more issues. The same BT issues on initial test, and a battery issue that started occuring the second day. The device would restart while attempting to charge. Eventually it would not power on when charging. I left it plugged in anyways and burnt my fingers when I went to go check on it about 30 minutes later. I thought this device might be a fire hazard so I picked it up with oven mits and placed it outside on cement to cool down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This required going through customer service again. They were nice enough to send me a care package this time around which included a Beatles and 2am album in MQS format for my troubles. They also sent me another replacement unit. Unfortunately the third device put me back to where I was with the first one. The BT issues are in fact an issue of the unit and I did not have a defective unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;m giving this device a low rating, I think A&amp;amp;K have something close to great here. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review in the hopes they read it and fix a few things to make their products up to par with the asking price. In all honesty, I probably would&amp;rsquo;ve kept the device had it not been for the poor BT support. I think they are valuing their aesthetic design too much and compromising on ergonomics. The buttons and case need some serious work and it&amp;rsquo;s not that hard of a fix. I think they just about hit the nail on the head with their UI and just need to make a minor tweak with the back button.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Popovy Girls
          
            - Inspired by the Popovy Dolls
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 66 Aug 10647 06:06:06 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I dedicated a photoshoot to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://popovy-dolls.com/&#34; title=&#34;Popovy Dolls&#34;&gt;Popovy Dolls&lt;/a&gt; who continue to be an inspiration of art. I put together a small team consisting of a makeup artist, hair stylist, and models who were intrigued by my vision. I took on the responsibility of photography, wardrobes, props, and final presentations. These are the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rose&#34;&gt;Rose&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-rose-tempt-994x663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-rose-pond-994x663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-rose-touch-994x663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;swan&#34;&gt;Swan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-swan1-663x663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-swan2-994x663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;red&#34;&gt;Red&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-red-663x663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mantis&#34;&gt;Mantis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-mantis1-586x586.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-mantis2-643x643.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bts&#34;&gt;BTS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-bts0-750x500.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-bts1-750x500.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-bts2-750x500.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/shoots/popovy-girls/popovy-girls-bts3-750x500.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was a labor of love with months of planning and decision making. From hair (+wigs), makeup, nails, clothes, and props. This was no easy task and not possible as a solo project. Many thanks to Erin Geer, Erica Cervantes, and Hugo Maldonado.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Leica M10 Review
          
            - A compilation of annoyances
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/leica-m10-review-a-compilation-of-annoyances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 106 Aug 51047 10:10:10 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/leica-m10-review-a-compilation-of-annoyances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sure, Ive been giving Leica a lot of praise in my posts because its really that great of a company that focuses on the essentials but its not all rainbows and unicorns. Youd expect such a high valued item to be closer to perfect but here are some things that could be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-camera&#34;&gt;On Camera&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small rangefinder patch:&lt;/strong&gt; Ive seen worst [looking at you Hasselblad Xpan] but I would like an explanation why the M3 was able to have such a large rangefinder patch while future models got smaller. I cant imagine why anyone would say, yes, yes make their lives harder and they will pay more for it! in a Dr. Evil voice. Is it because newer lenses have a closer focusing distances than the vintage ones? Is it because the M3 was originally designed for 50mm lenses (and above) that somehow makes it possible? I would appreciate a drop in the comments if you know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frame lines startup lag:&lt;/strong&gt; Anything less than instant is unacceptable when all the film variants starting with the very first M camera (the M3), had the capabilities to display frame lines at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top cover plate:&lt;/strong&gt; My main issue with this is the face design. The illumination window for bright frame lines is gone (maybe this is why the digital frame lines take forever to show up?) and the viewfinder doesnt sit above the lovely classic bevel that was once there on all other prior models. Its too minimal.  I get it, its a bit more of a modern look but its a bit boring and too streamlined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear display:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a two part issue. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to complain about the display resolution for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HPIJJq&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Digital Rangefinder Camera (Silver)&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36scWZs&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10-P Digital Rangefinder Camera 20021 (Black Chrome)&#34;&gt;M10-P&lt;/a&gt;, maybe it was ok for 2017? However, no increase in quality with the M10-R is a bit sad especially when the &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; means resolution. Secondly, the cosmetics of the screen. Why is it not centered within the margins? Ive seen this issue on other cameras recently so I guess its just one company making these parts but I would imagine Leica with its price point can demand something a little more acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self timing lever:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HPIJJq&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Digital Rangefinder Camera (Silver)&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt; series is definitely the closest resemblance to the film Leicas and I think it couldve been that much better if they returned with the self timing lever. One less reason for me to go into the menus wouldve made the experience that much better. I love it on the M3 and I think the M6/7/P couldve just been almost perfect if they had it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WiFi/Leica app:&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe I would let the self timer issue go if the phone app wasnt horribly slow. Its ok&amp;rsquo;ish once you get it connected but it takes handful of moments to startup. Better than nothing in a pinch but most times I&amp;rsquo;d rather not use it at all with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HPIJJq&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Digital Rangefinder Camera (Silver)&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe they shouldve got rid of this too when they got rid of video? Jk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No silent shutter:&lt;/strong&gt; Its a digital camera so I dont understand why it doesnt have an option to take a photo without the shutter. I hope there is a better reason than the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HPIJJq&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Digital Rangefinder Camera (Silver)&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36scWZs&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10-P Digital Rangefinder Camera 20021 (Black Chrome)&#34;&gt;P&lt;/a&gt;/R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;accessories&#34;&gt;Accessories&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2GxH6j0&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Thumb Support (black)&#34;&gt;Leica M10 Thumb Support&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the Match Technical thumbs up grip came out first and Leica tried to get some of that market by making their own &amp;ldquo;knock off&amp;rdquo;. It uses the exact same black or silver paint as the camera which is probably the only thing it has going for it. (But honestly I cant tell a difference of paint with the Match Technical version.) Its also Leica branded which means its excessively overpriced. The issue I have with this thumb grip is that its a quarter circle cut without the ergonomic design of the Match Technical version. Why bother releasing an additional accessory if you cant make it better than what has become the standard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3lhwhkj&#34; title=&#34;Leica Visoflex (Typ 020) Electronic Viewfinder&#34;&gt;Leica Visoflex Typ 020&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Another almost useless accessory. I thought it would make life easier when shooting summilux lenses wide open while adding the ability to look straight down into your camera. It kindve does but it also makes the camera too slow. The resolution is the worst Ive seen in a long while, and it protrudes over the shutter dial. I know it was originally made for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HMNaoj&#34; title=&#34;Leica 018-180 T 16 MP Mirrorless Digital Camera with 3.7-Inch LCD, Black Anodized&#34;&gt;Leica T&lt;/a&gt; system and I guess its just an added perk that it works for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HPIJJq&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Digital Rangefinder Camera (Silver)&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt;. It wouldve been nice if they had one that followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2HPIJJq&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10 Digital Rangefinder Camera (Silver)&#34;&gt;M10s&lt;/a&gt; aesthetics. Then again, if it worked a lot more fluid I probably wouldnt have bought a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3ngVsoP&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;SL2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Actually, an M10R and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3lhwhkj&#34; title=&#34;Leica Visoflex (Typ 020) Electronic Viewfinder&#34;&gt;Visoflex&lt;/a&gt; worth its money would be amazing! Maybe M11 will fix this but I wouldnt hold my breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thats all I have which are mostly minor cosmetic and nitpick issues. No camera is perfect but the Leica M series is closest for me in the digital realm. All I can hope is someone at Leica reads this and takes it for consideration in the next versions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Sony A7R Review
          
            - The camera that does it all
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/sony-a7r-iii-review-3-years-of-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 76 Aug 300733 07:07:07 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/sony-a7r-iii-review-3-years-of-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This review is not a spec review but a personal review of the Sony camera system. At the time of this writing, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2FB07B8&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R IV Full-frame Mirrorless Interchangeable Lens Camera (ILCE7RM4/B)&#34;&gt;Sony A7R IV&lt;/a&gt; has already been out for 10 months and I have already parted ways with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3kwrg72&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R III Mirrorless Camera: 42.4MP Full Frame High Resolution Interchangeable Lens Digital Camera with Front End LSI Image Processor, 4K HDR Video and 3&amp;quot; LCD Screen - ILCE7RM3/B Body, Black&#34;&gt;A7R III&lt;/a&gt; six months ago. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t for a direct upgrade because I feel like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3kwrg72&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R III Mirrorless Camera: 42.4MP Full Frame High Resolution Interchangeable Lens Digital Camera with Front End LSI Image Processor, 4K HDR Video and 3&amp;quot; LCD Screen - ILCE7RM3/B Body, Black&#34;&gt;A7R III&lt;/a&gt; was already good or better than good enough for most things. On the contrary, I opted for a completely manual system with less features on a spec sheet. Part of the reason for this was due to how my shooting style evolved. Ill explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewinding back to the time when I was reintroducing myself to photography, I wanted the best there was. I was previously a Canon fanboy in another life but the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3myNsPF&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R II Full-Frame Mirrorless Interchangeable Lens Camera, Body Only (Black) (ILCE7RM2/B), Base, Base&#34;&gt;Sony A7R II&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be all the hype. Doing some research, it seemed Sony was releasing cameras every 2 years and was ahead of the curve in technology. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to drop a whole lot of money in the middle of A7R releases when there was this kick a** &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Fy1YXp&#34; title=&#34;Sony Alpha A6600 Mirrorless Camera&#34;&gt;a6500&lt;/a&gt; just released that produced similar results while using the same lens mount. Ultimately, sharp photos and superior autofocus is what I was looking for in a tool to document my daughter growing up. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Fy1YXp&#34; title=&#34;Sony Alpha A6600 Mirrorless Camera&#34;&gt;a6500&lt;/a&gt; was a great stepping stone to learn and building up my arsenal while I fantasized about shooting with a full frame sensor when the time was right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot by documenting my daughter growing up. How to use the camera in and out: compositions, video, lighting, studio equipment, just about everything one can learn. And I&amp;rsquo;m still learning. I fell down the rabbit hole and the Sony system is probably one of the best to do that with since it did everything well. And that&amp;rsquo;s what I wanted, something that did everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3kwrg72&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R III Mirrorless Camera: 42.4MP Full Frame High Resolution Interchangeable Lens Digital Camera with Front End LSI Image Processor, 4K HDR Video and 3&amp;quot; LCD Screen - ILCE7RM3/B Body, Black&#34;&gt;A7R III&lt;/a&gt; was announced and I jumped on it. It filled the needed void in me and I felt like it could do anything. I documented family events, and evolved to paid events and studio headshots. It paired perfectly with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Fy1YXp&#34; title=&#34;Sony Alpha A6600 Mirrorless Camera&#34;&gt;a6500&lt;/a&gt; when needing to shoot video from multiple angles. Not to mention the system worked great with popular software and hardware vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time went on, I let go of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Fy1YXp&#34; title=&#34;Sony Alpha A6600 Mirrorless Camera&#34;&gt;a6500&lt;/a&gt; to acquire more full frame lenses. I didnt need multiple camera bodies for video that often and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t bringing it out to shoot anymore. About a year into it and a few family vacations later, I started to get burnt out by the camera weight I was traveling with. I was realizing that I dont take really take much video and most times I hate changing lenses. I also didnt like the huge camera slung around my shoulder and the way it looked on me in other peoples pictures. It started to feel big and obnoxious. It was probably the smallest and full frame body with an interchangeable lens system on the market with the best spec sheet but once you slapped a lens on it then it was as big (or bigger) than most DSLR setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to look at other options available from different vendors. Being a full frame snob at the time, I found the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2RGXjEI&#34; title=&#34;Sony Cyber-shot DSC-RX1 RII Digital Still Camera&#34;&gt;Sony RXR1&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2RLAVtP&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera (Black, Anodized, TYP 116)&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt;. Leica was something I started to fantasize about but I never thought I would ever make the jump because its price point is ridiculous compared to what you get with Sony&amp;hellip; or any other manufacturer for that matter. Long story short, I added a Leica Q to the family and you can read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/&#34;&gt;my experience with it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2RLAVtP&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera (Black, Anodized, TYP 116)&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; was going to be a little home wrecker to the happy Sony family I had going on. It ended up being the camera I took with me everywhere and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3kwrg72&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R III Mirrorless Camera: 42.4MP Full Frame High Resolution Interchangeable Lens Digital Camera with Front End LSI Image Processor, 4K HDR Video and 3&amp;quot; LCD Screen - ILCE7RM3/B Body, Black&#34;&gt;A7R III&lt;/a&gt; got left behind unless it was a studio or paid shoot. I tried using them together a few times but the color profiles to me were just too different and making them look the same in post was another headache I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something in me was changing. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2RLAVtP&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera (Black, Anodized, TYP 116)&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; was a well dressed full frame camera that I was happy to take with me everywhere and the Sony was better for larger projects thanks to its tethering and autofocus capabilities. My larger projects were few and far between but shooting is something I enjoyed doing everyday. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2RLAVtP&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera (Black, Anodized, TYP 116)&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; left me still wanting more than a well dressed camera. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what exactly but I wanted something to spark my creative soul. I gave an M3 a shot. I thought it was a lot of work to get a single shot. Everything was manual: Focusing, metering, winding the film, developing, scanning, etc&amp;hellip; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect in terms of the results since the last time I shot film it was a disposable camera many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so thrilled when I got my photos back. Truthfully, not all were great shots, but the ones that were good are some of my favorites even today. There is something about the workflow of each shot. The experience was completely different from my Sony experience which was more like machine gun shooting. I always resulted with a far less shots when using my Leica M3 but a lot more keepers that I am happy with instead of hundreds (or thousands) of photos that needed to be culled and edited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I knew I wanted more of that slower but rewarding experience. I wanted to spend more time working on my shot and less time in post. Yes, it could&amp;rsquo;ve been done with the Sony but it&amp;rsquo;s different when the tool forces you to work in a different way. Time went on and I started accumulating more M lenses and bodies to &amp;ldquo;complete&amp;rdquo; the digital/film range. Eventually an opportunity came along to part ways with all my Sony gear in exchange for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3iLgdGm&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;Leica SL2&lt;/a&gt;. This was a difficult decision for me. Tough financially because I would be swapping out my Sony body and my lenses for only a single &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3iLgdGm&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;Leica SL2&lt;/a&gt; body. Emotional because the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3kwrg72&#34; title=&#34;Sony a7R III Mirrorless Camera: 42.4MP Full Frame High Resolution Interchangeable Lens Digital Camera with Front End LSI Image Processor, 4K HDR Video and 3&amp;quot; LCD Screen - ILCE7RM3/B Body, Black&#34;&gt;A7R III&lt;/a&gt; was the first camera I dreamt about, taught me so much, and has been on so many family adventures. But the truth was, it was already retired from family adventures due to its size and bulk. I needed to be practical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, I made the right decision because I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed my Sony gear once since packaging it up and sending it to its new owner&amp;hellip; Except while writing this post, heh. I hope its out there teaching somebody all the possibilities of digital shooting and creating great new memories because at the end the only thing that matters are the photos and experiences people shared together. Thank you Sony for getting me back into photography and helping me figure out what I wanted to do with it :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Leica Q Review
          
            - The Gateway Drug
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 76 Aug 250738 07:07:07 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its been exactly two years now since Ive purchased my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica&lt;/a&gt;, the Q. It was right around this time when I was going on a birthday trip to Mexico. I was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2BwEEHk&#34; title=&#34;Sony A7R III&#34;&gt;Sony A7R&lt;/a&gt; shooter and I believed then what I still do now: the Sony system is the most technological advanced system out there that delivered some of the sharpest results Ive ever seen. But what it was lacking is what I was looking for in Leica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of trips around the world prior had me realize that I dont want to be the person carrying around a backpack full of lenses and a large camera body. I wanted my family trips documented in the highest quality but at the same time what are supposed to be a trips of leisure and quality time shouldnt feel like trips of added work&amp;hellip; Thus the search for smaller systems&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;options&#34;&gt;Options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a full frame snob at the time didnt leave me with too many &amp;ldquo;compact&amp;rdquo; camera options. In the left corner we had the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZZeFlo&#34; title=&#34;Sony Cyber-shot DSC-RX1 RII&#34;&gt;Sony RX1R&lt;/a&gt; and on the right we had &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt;. They both would bring the relief of not having to decide what lens to bring out everyday of a trip and physically (and mentalluy) lighten the load. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZZeFlo&#34; title=&#34;Sony Cyber-shot DSC-RX1 RII&#34;&gt;RX1R&lt;/a&gt; would have fit right at home with my Sony arsenal without a question. A unified menu system throughout my camera bodies, a seamless post processing process, 35mm f2 lens, ~$2k less and twice the megapixels against its competition is definitely added value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the right corner, Leica packing a 28mm f1.7 lens with macro for added fun is a nice perk! There is usually a family group picture on my trips where I find 35mm is the narrowest lens I would like for these occasions. Sometimes my family is too large or sometimes I want to capture more of the environment. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2D6r4eb&#34; title=&#34;Sony Carl Zeiss Sonnar T E 24mm F1.8 ZA E-mount Prime Lens&#34;&gt;24mm f1.8 Zeiss&lt;/a&gt; in the past has been my favorite for these group shots but circling back to fixed lens cameras, the 28mm on Leica comes in favorable compared to the 35mm on the Sony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok so the lens was already a selling point to me. Any Leica shooter will also tell you that a  28mm Summilux M lens a la carte will run you $7k. That means no autofocus, no camera body, and no macro support which implies that the Leica Q is a steal. And they are right but Ive never spent much over $2k on a lens at the time. My bread and butter was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/39vaeSh&#34; title=&#34;Sony SEL90M28G FE 90mm f/2.8-22 Macro G OSS Standard-Prime Lens&#34;&gt;Sony FE 90mm 2.8 macro lens&lt;/a&gt; which only cost me $1k so I thought they were all just a little insane&amp;hellip; Or maybe it was something I just didnt understand yet? I was intrigued but the Leica pill was a big one swallow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decision-time&#34;&gt;Decision Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time was running out and I had to make decision. Searching for a deal, I found a Leica Q for sale online from a local pawn shop. Sketchy as it sounds, I had to investigate. The serial number checked out and I was able to haggle them a little on the price&amp;hellip;But the best deal I could get it for was the the price of a brand new &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZZeFlo&#34; title=&#34;Sony Cyber-shot DSC-RX1 RII&#34;&gt;Sony RX1R&lt;/a&gt;. Its scary knowing that its a final sale with no warranty once the transaction is complete. I mean, its a pawn shop camera!? But I already knew after holding it in my hand that I had to have it. There is a mechanically engineered feel to it that was elegant and precise. The shutter dial and aperture ring were right where they should be. Sure the menu system was different but it was world of simplicity inside and out compared to Sony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The images were not as sharp out of the camera as what I was used to but sharp enough. On the other hand, the colors were pleasant which IMO is more important. Hard to explain but it works for me. And lastly, its just aesthetically a beautiful camera that makes you feel proud to wear. Sure it&amp;rsquo;s just a piece of tech gear at the end of the day but the classic look, well, keeps it timeless. That probably plays a role in keeping Leica products from obsolescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trip-conclusion&#34;&gt;Trip Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at it objectively, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to say the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; is just an digital camera in a Leica aesthetic and you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wrong at all. You would be exactly right. You could even think of it of an electric motor in a vintage Porsche body. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a nod to the M line. But if you&amp;rsquo;re just comparing the spec sheets then its easy to say the Leica is overpriced for what you get and technically you are right too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are you buying? Well, you&amp;rsquo;re getting a unique experience that only you can say if it&amp;rsquo;s worth it as it&amp;rsquo;s purely subjective but I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to explain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; get the essential controls on your camera that greatly simplifies the shooting experience. This alone makes the camera feel more like, as they say, an extension of you. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s digital camera, it feels less technical than all other digital cameras. The shooting experience is slower thus leaving my trip with less photos but unexpectingly more keepers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side effects of slower shooting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being more selective of your shots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being in the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not snapping shots of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saving time culling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the experience may be defined as making a photograph rather than taking a snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-gateway&#34;&gt;The Gateway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what do you being one foot in? Taking photos are a little more work and there is less tech. You&amp;rsquo;d be kidding yourself if you think you couldn&amp;rsquo;t achieve the similar results on another camera sytem. At this point you have an idea where you stand. I think there are a few routes and if you knew already this was not for you then you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gotten this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Route 1: You stop at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; not because you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in more but because you&amp;rsquo;re not a studio photographer so no point in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3k3EKru&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;SL&lt;/a&gt;. You might also wear glasses making using an M just too much headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Route 2: You need to undertsand how people live with themselves using a rangefinder with no autofocus lenses. The mini size of these full frame lens intrigues you further down the rabbit hole. Not to mention the backwards compatability the M bodies have with M lenses since the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Route 3: Maybe the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3k3EKru&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;SL&lt;/a&gt; starts seeming like a fantastic workflow option for your studio needs? The simplified menu sytem and slowing down just sold you on the kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Route 4: (Spoiler alert: This is where I end up.) A combination of #2 and #3. I bought into the M system and haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back. I tried the M lenses on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2BwEEHk&#34; title=&#34;Sony A7R III&#34;&gt;Sony A7R&lt;/a&gt; and the feel just wasn&amp;rsquo;t right. I demo&amp;rsquo;d my M lenses on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3k3EKru&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;Leica SL2&lt;/a&gt; when it came out. They felt right at home and now I consolidated my lens to M mount. This has been working for me great in studio, casually and street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;now&#34;&gt;Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later and this brand with their essentials philosophies has infiltrated my photography. I still own the Q as it compliments my now Leica ecosystem just right with its macro and wide angle lens. I tried parting with on several occasions like when the Q2 was added to the family but its become an emotional attachment. The little pawn shop camera is part of the family. When I go out, an M camera usually comes with me. Rangefinder took less getting used to than youd think. It removes a lot of technical/digital thinking from the shooting experience when taking your shots. Focusing with it has become a breeze and the preferred way to use a camera. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3k3EKru&#34; title=&#34;Leica SL2 Mirrorless Camera Body&#34;&gt;SL2&lt;/a&gt; is now my studio camera and uses only M lenses for the time being. The Q comes out when there is more of a group setting. It&amp;rsquo;s also great when I know I&amp;rsquo;m going somewhere where I&amp;rsquo;d like the camera to be passed to someone else to take a photo. There is a &amp;ldquo;Touch AF + Release&amp;rdquo; feature on it that allows someone to touch the the back of the screen to autofocus and take the picture. This has been when handing the camera to novices for snapshots. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; has definitely been a gateway drug&amp;hellip; And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even end with photography, wait till you put your eyes in their binoculars. I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030530.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02_DSC0086.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030634.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030687.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030717.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030728.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02_DSC0167.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030696.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030953.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02_DSC0282.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.02L1030996.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040045.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040065.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040136.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040190.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040226.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040441.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03L1040574.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.03_DSC0574.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.04_DSC1204.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.04_DSC4663.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.04L1040623.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/leica-q-review-the-gateway-drug/2018-08-14+00.28.05_DSC5219.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Add cursive fonts to VS Code
          
            - Fira Code
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/apps/ide/visual-studio-code/how-to-add-cursive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 66 Aug 140657 06:06:06 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/apps/ide/visual-studio-code/how-to-add-cursive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently got into caligraphy and thought it would be neat to see cursive in my code editor as well. A quick google and I found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tonsky/FiraCode&#34; title=&#34;Fira Code&#34;&gt;monospaced cursive font with ligatures&lt;/a&gt;! (Ligatures are basically symbols that replace pieces of code like &lt;code&gt;!==&lt;/code&gt; to single looking character.) It&amp;rsquo;s really nice and makes some things very easy to read on top of making the coding experience a little more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll first need to download &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tonsky/FiraCode&#34; title=&#34;Fira Code&#34;&gt;Fira Code&lt;/a&gt; fonts and install them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and apply &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=idbartosz.darkpp-italic&#34; title=&#34;Dark++ Italic&#34;&gt;Dark++ Italic&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34; title=&#34;Visual Studio Code - Code Editing&#34;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;settings.json&lt;/code&gt; file and add the following lines:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; title=&#34;settings.json&#34; &gt;{
    &#34;editor.fontFamily&#34;: &#34;Fira Code iScript, Menlo, Monaco, &#39;Courier New&#39;, monospace&#34;,
    &#34;editor.fontLigatures&#34;: true,
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could be done at this point if you are fine with the Dark++ Italic theme colors. Or you could add these additional settings to your &lt;code&gt;settings.json&lt;/code&gt; to override any themes&#39; font configuration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; I added a some additional &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt; that Dark++ Italic didn&amp;rsquo;t have, like &lt;code&gt;comment&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; title=&#34;settings.json&#34;&gt;{
    &#34;editor.tokenColorCustomizations&#34;: {
        &#34;textMateRules&#34;: [
            {
                &#34;name&#34;: &#34;comment&#34;,
                &#34;scope&#34;: [
                    &#34;comment&#34;
                ],
                &#34;settings&#34;: {
                    &#34;fontStyle&#34;: &#34;italic&#34;
                }
            },
            {
                &#34;name&#34;: &#34;Keyword Storage&#34;,
                &#34;scope&#34;: [
                    &#34;keyword&#34;,
                    &#34;keyword.control&#34;,
                    &#34;storage&#34;
                ],
                &#34;settings&#34;: {
                    &#34;fontStyle&#34;: &#34;italic&#34;
                }
            },
            {
                &#34;name&#34;: &#34;Entity&#34;,
                &#34;scope&#34;: [
                    &#34;entity.name.method&#34;,
                    &#34;entity.name.type.class&#34;,
                    &#34;entity.other.attribute-name&#34;
                ],
                &#34;settings&#34;: {
                    &#34;fontStyle&#34;: &#34;italic&#34;
                }
            },
            {
                &#34;name&#34;: &#34;Variable&#34;,
                &#34;scope&#34;: [
                    &#34;variable.language&#34;
                ],
                &#34;settings&#34;: {
                    &#34;fontStyle&#34;: &#34;italic&#34;
                }
            }
        ]
    }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While taking notes can sometimes seem boring, it can be fun with a nice pen, some ink, and the right notepad. Adding Dark++ Italic and Fira Code does that to my IDE. There are also other monospaced cursive fonts out there like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kiliman/operator-mono-lig&#34; title=&#34;Operator Mono Lig&#34;&gt;Operator Mono Lig&lt;/a&gt;, for example. Try some out and see what works for you. Have fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Vi Vante Review
          
            - The Epitome of Luxury Camera Straps
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 66 Aug 40633 06:06:06 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ooo hello there Matador Noir! Now thats a good looking strap. &amp;hellip; What?!? $250!!! For a camera strap??? Yeah, those were my exact thoughts when I first laid my eyes on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/matador-noir&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Matador Noir&amp;quot; The World&#39;s Most Luxurious Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Matador Noir&lt;/a&gt;. I glanced at a few pictures and thought &lt;em&gt;yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty nice&lt;/em&gt;. Glanced at the price, sighed, and closed my browser tab. A year has passed since then and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; camera straps have been my exclusive choice of leather on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2XXqZAm&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10&#34;&gt;Leica M&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Q&lt;/a&gt; bodies. But how did this happen? How did I let this seemingly overpriced looking brand take over my precious Leica collection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, it was quite obvious. I never really found the perfect camera strap for my Leica cameras. Like most people, I started off with whatever came with the camera. My first Leica was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/30i3CV5&#34; title=&#34;Leica Q 24.2 Megapixel Digital 35 MM Compact Camera&#34;&gt;Leica Q&lt;/a&gt; that I picked up at a sketchy pawn shop. It came with a nice silky rope strap which was ok, not really me, but I ran with it anyways. As you know, get one Leica and it wont be your last&amp;hellip; I then got a M3 that came with guitar style strap. It was very hippie and not really me either. At this point I started experimenting with various leather straps. Short, long, adjustable, with a pad, anything and everything. You name it, I had it. The Leica infection I had was spreading simultaneously and once I believed I needed a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2XXqZAm&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10&#34;&gt;M10&lt;/a&gt;, well I got one. Not impressed with the standard strap, I went to a Leica gallery and picked what looked like should be a great strap that a sales person had to pull from behind the glass shelves. It was popular German brand (I wont mention their name) I see at a lot of Leica galleries so I figure it should be decent. Spent about $169.00 + taxes. It was made from a nice whiskey leather, had a decent pad that was big enough to not feel the weight of the Leica choking you yet thin enough to keep that slim look. It was supple out of the box unlike other straps that required a break in period. It was perfect until not too long after the threading started to frail. This became annoying if you could imagine having to trim the loose ends every so often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if this well established German brand couldnt make camera straps right, then who is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; to think they can come and solve all the problems Ive been having? I had my doubts and was skeptical to buy a high priced strap from them with no reviews to be found online. But a the same time I&amp;rsquo;ve been wondering what does a camera strap demanding over $200 feel like? I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s literally a strap with rings at each end right? But who am I to judge especially what I paid for a manual Leica camera? I opened a dialog to them and they seemed very responsive and easy to talk to which was the first green light. However, time for me was running short because I was soon to be going on a vacation and I didnt want to use my existing straps. The one that requires an occasionally trim just looks bad and the others were just too thin that caused neck and shoulder pain like someone is trying to choke you with a piano wire if you tried wearing them longer than hour. I needed something that could last me a whole day of being a tourist without causing neck or shoulder discomfort. I needed to be able to wear my camera all day and have it by my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi Vante replied and suggested the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/matador-noir&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Matador Noir&amp;quot; The World&#39;s Most Luxurious Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Matador Noir&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ultime-blackout&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Ultime&amp;quot; Blackout Braided Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Ultime&lt;/a&gt; would be fine with my M bodies and Summilux lenses. In a pinch, I ordered both, one from Amazon and one directly from Vi Vante because I was worried one wouldnt get to me before I depart to Europe. I thought I would just keep whichever one arrived first and probably return the other. However their shipping was extremely fast and both straps arrived to me at nearly the same time leaving much time to spare. They came in a nice little box with beautiful wrapping. The strap was in the box in a nice custom pouch. Basically packaged the way you should expect when purchasing luxury items. I pulled them out and was amazed at the quality as soon as I touched the leather! It was amongst, if not, the softest and most supple leathers I have ever felt. How they are able to achieve such a thick and tight braid while keeping the straps free forming is impressive to say the least. I find products that require a break in period first (like some shoes) are kind&amp;rsquo;ve annoying. A great product to me is something that is ready out of the box and only gets better with time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; delivered precisely that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate further, the straps can easily be wrapped around your wrist or crumbled in your palm without much resistance and easily fall back into their natural shape when released. The leather doesnt require your body oil and sweat to be massaged into it for months to soften it and give character as they say. The under side of the strap which lays on your body is just as beautiful as the top because there are clearly no shortcuts taken. The straps being so flexible have actually made it easy for me to toss my camera in a bag without it being a nuisance. The width is just right for up to a Summilux lens and can makes your camera setup feel almost weightless with a Summicron. (I dont have any Notctiluxes to test with.) And how many of you have your black Leica, black lens, black camera strap, but break your continuity with silver camera strap rings? I thought that was an annoying thing only I cared about but all &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; straps come with electroplated gun metal rings! Isnt that the icing on the cake or what? It seems like a small detail but if youre reading this and youre a Leica shooter then you know its all about the small details and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante&lt;/a&gt; gets it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One minor shortcoming is their straps are all 49 long. Im 511 and that actually works for me pretty well. I thought Id miss the ability to jack up my camera to my arm pits when Im in action mode. I usually compensate by either throwing my camera in my sling or wrap the strap around my wrist snake style. My fianc however is about 54 and the straps are a bit too long for her&amp;hellip; Sorry short people. On the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s kind&amp;rsquo;ve nice because I didn&amp;rsquo;t always like how the slider looked on my shirt especially when it was metal thus making it attention grabing. Like a Leica, these straps are extremely simple to use so there is no need to fiddle with anything while being a design masterpiece at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I ended up keeping both straps for my trip and applied the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ultime-blackout&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Ultime&amp;quot; Blackout Braided Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Ultime&lt;/a&gt; to my m3 and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/matador-noir&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante &amp;quot;Matador Noir&amp;quot; The World&#39;s Most Luxurious Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Matadoir Noir&lt;/a&gt; to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2XXqZAm&#34; title=&#34;Leica M10&#34;&gt;m10&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Yeah, yeah Im one of those guys who brings multiple cameras on a vacation. I know, I cant help it. Im getting better though, I promise :) Fast forward to today, Im the proud owner of more Vi Vante straps than I have Leicas. Ive added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ultime-phoenix&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Ultime Phoenix Red Black Braided Leather Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Ultime Phoenix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/camerastraps/ascari/nardo&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Ascari Nardo Gray Napa Leather 47&amp;quot; Camera Strap&#34;&gt;Ascari Nardo Gray&lt;/a&gt;, and my new current favorite&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3cD09mx&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Tiger Braided Luxury Lambskin Leather&#34;&gt;The Tiger Luxury Lambskin&lt;/a&gt;. You just have to feel that lambskin leather. Im all about the supple leathers and this feels as flexible as a cotton strap. Unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re a wrist strap person, then I have to say yes they&amp;rsquo;ve also made the best wrist strap I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/374A3r9&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Bengal Unleashed Black Leather Camera Wrist Strap Ultra Soft Lambskin&#34;&gt;ViVante Bengal Unleashed&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s basically &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3cD09mx&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante Tiger Braided Luxury Lambskin Leather&#34;&gt;The Tiger&lt;/a&gt; strap shortened for your wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other little perks of having a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vi-vante.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vi Vante designer leather camera straps and more&#34;&gt;Vi Vante strap&lt;/a&gt;. Its hard to explain but it brings me joy when seeing how the strap falls beautifully around the camera when setting it down on a table. Its a small thing but if you own one of these straps then you might understand what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if youre an admirer of the Leicas precision, design, and have been yearning for a camera strap to finally match the standards that it demands, then look no further. I dont think youll be dissatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/vi-vante-tiger-richard-coffee.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/vi-vante-tiger-richard-steps.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/photography/gear/vi-vante-review/vi-vante-tiger-richard-wrapped.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Cinestill C-41 Development Times
          
            - Chemical Reuse
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/chemicals/cinestill-c41-developer-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 56 Aug 240553 05:05:05 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/photography/chemicals/cinestill-c41-developer-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find my table of development times for color negative film using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freestylephoto.biz/800341-CineStill-Cs41-Liquid-Developing-Kit-for-C-41-Color-Film-1-Quart&#34; title=&#34;CineStill Cs41 Liquid Developing Kit for C-41 Color Film - 1 Quart&#34;&gt;Cinestill C-41 kit&lt;/a&gt; at 102 degrees F. These notes should work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2X1InEV&#34; title=&#34;Arista C-41 kit&#34;&gt;Arista C-41&lt;/a&gt; as well since the instructions are nearly identical for chemical reuse. Heck, it might even be the same stuff, just repackaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s handy to print this out and save it in your lab for quick references. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to put a piece of &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/36pujrR&#34; title=&#34;Gapher tape&#34;&gt;gapher tape&lt;/a&gt; on your &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eaOjAU&#34; title=&#34;Amber boston round chemistry bottles&#34;&gt;chemistry bottles&lt;/a&gt; used for storage and mark how many rolls have been developed with them by a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2TBjj5j&#34; title=&#34;Sharpie permanent markers&#34;&gt;sharpie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table-bordered table-center&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Rolls Processed&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;i&gt;new chemistry&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:30&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:34&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:38&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:43&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:47&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:51&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:30&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3:59&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:04&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:08&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:12&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:16&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:25&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:29&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:33&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:37&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:41&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:46&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:50&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4:54&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way to read this is not by how many rolls you are going to develop, but how many rolls have already been developed. For example, if I were going to develop 5 rolls with fresh chemistry then I would start at 0. The next batch will start at 5 and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually develop batches of five 35mm rolls at a time (or the 120 equivelant) while reusing my chemicals for up to 15 rolls. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen a shift in the quality as I&amp;rsquo;ve developed more rolls through the same chemistry. I can probably use 1 quart for 20 or so rolls but I&amp;rsquo;ve never stocked up on that film that needed to be developed at once. The nightmare of scanning the film lurking around the corner is just too much for me to bare. Just keep in mind the longer you keep your chemicals and expose to air, then the weaker they become&amp;hellip; If I have chemicals sit, it will only be for a week or two in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eaOjAU&#34; title=&#34;Amber boston round chemistry bottles&#34;&gt;sealed bottle&lt;/a&gt; that is light safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pushpull&#34;&gt;Push/Pull&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not something I like doing with my color negative film. I&amp;rsquo;m typically not a fan of the look and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to develop my film in batches unless I am pushing/pulling all the film in my development container&amp;hellip; Black and white may be a different story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Privacy Policy
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 56 Aug 220547 05:05:05 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about the policy, or practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Privacy Policy governs the privacy policies and practices of the Website, located at RichardSumilang.com and its sub domains. Please read the Privacy Policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;information-collected&#34;&gt;Information Collected&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Visitor, you can browse the Website to find out more about the Website. You are not required to provide any personal information as a Visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;automatically-collected-information&#34;&gt;Automatically Collected Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use the Website, we automatically collect certain computer information by the interaction of your mobile phone or web browser with our Website. Such information is typically considered non-personal information. We also collect the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cookies&#34;&gt;Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Website uses &amp;ldquo;Cookies&amp;rdquo; to identify the areas of our Website that you have visited. A Cookie is a small piece of data stored on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. We use Cookies to personalize the Content that you see on our Website. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of Cookies. However, if you disable Cookies, you may not be able to access functionality on our Website correctly or at all. We never place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;log-information&#34;&gt;Log Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information includes the name of the website from which you entered our Website, if any, as well as the name of the website to which you&amp;rsquo;re headed when you leave our website. This information also includes the IP address of your computer/proxy server that you use to access the Internet, your Internet Website provider name, web browser type, type of mobile device, and computer operating system. We use all of this information to analyze trends among our Users to help improve our Website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;information-regarding-your-data-protection-rights-under-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr&#34;&gt;Information Regarding Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information, as described in this Privacy Policy, depends on the information we collect and the specific context in which we collect it. We may process your personal information because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to perform a contract with you, such as when you use our services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have given us permission to do so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The processing is in our legitimate interests and it&amp;rsquo;s not overridden by your rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To comply with the law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to access, update or to delete the personal information we have on you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right of rectification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right of restriction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to data portability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to withdraw consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that you may be asked to verify your identity before responding to such requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-not-sell-my-personal-information-notice-for-california-consumers-under-california-consumer-privacy-act-ccpa&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Not Sell My Personal Information&amp;rdquo; Notice for California consumers under California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the CCPA, California consumers have the right to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request that a business that collects a consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data disclose the categories and specific pieces of personal data that a business has collected about consumers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request that a business delete any personal data about the consumer that a business has collected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request that a business that sells a consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data, not sell the consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;service-providers&#34;&gt;Service Providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third party companies are employed and individuals to facilitate our Website (&amp;ldquo;Service Providers&amp;rdquo;), to provide our Website on our behalf, to perform Website-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Website is used. These third-parties have access to your personal information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analytics&#34;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy &amp;amp; Terms web page: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;payments-processors&#34;&gt;Payments processors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid products and/or services on our Website are occassionally provided. In that case, a third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors) will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your payment card details will not be stored. That information is provided directly to a third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Terms and Conditions
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 56 Aug 220547 05:05:05 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/about/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-overview&#34;&gt;A. Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the website RichardSumilang.com (the Site).  The Site is an online service owned by Richard Sumilang (or Richard Sumilang Photography).  Richard Sumilang has created this Site for your personal enjoyment, education and entertainment.  This Terms of Use agreement (the Agreement) describes the terms and conditions under which Richard Sumilang permits your use of the Site, and any other services of Richard Sumilang that display this Agreement (collectively with the Site and services, the Services).  This Agreement constitutes a legal agreement between you and Richard Sumilang.  Use of this Site or any of the other Services is also governed by Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s Privacy Policy, which is incorporated into this Agreement by reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By viewing, interacting with, submitting information to, or otherwise using the Services, you agree to be bound by this Agreement.  If you do not wish to be bound by this Agreement, you must not use the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify, update, or otherwise change this Agreement at any time.  By using the Services after such changes are posted, you agree to be bound by the changes. &lt;strong&gt;This Agreement was last modified on May 22nd, 2020.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;b-intellectual-property&#34;&gt;B. Intellectual Property&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All content included in this Site or in or through the other Services, such as text, photos, logos, video, graphics, sound, computer code, and the arrangement and selection of such content, is protected by copyrights, and/or other intellectual property rights of Richard Sumilang and/or third-party content providers. The business names, logos, slogans, trade dress and all other marks on this Site or in the Services are copyrights of Richard Sumilang or related third-party content providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may use material from this Site or the Services only for your own personal, non-commercial use.  No portion of this Site or the other Services may be republished, reproduced, duplicated, copied, uploaded, downloaded, posted, transmitted, modified, sold, or otherwise exploited for any purpose that is not expressly permitted by Richard Sumilang.  In the event of any permitted copying, redistribution, or publication of copyrighted material, no changes in or deletion of trademarks, author attribution or copyright notices may be made. You acknowledge that you do not acquire any ownership rights by downloading material from this Site or the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe in good faith that your copyrighted work has been reproduced on this Site or through the Services without authorization in a way that constitutes copyright infringement, please send a notice of copyright infringement containing the following information to Richard Sumilang designated copyright agent by email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of the work or material being infringed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing, including its location, with sufficient detail so that we are capable of finding it and verifying its existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact information for the notifying party (the &amp;ldquo;Notifying Party&amp;rdquo;), including name, address, telephone number, and email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A statement that the Notifying Party has a good faith belief that the material is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent or law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A statement made under penalty of perjury that the information provided in the notice is accurate and that the Notifying Party is authorized to make the complaint on behalf of the copyright owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of the copyright that has been allegedly infringed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;c-submission-of-content-by-users&#34;&gt;C. Submission of Content by Users&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain places, this Site or the Services may allow users to submit comments, blog entries, letters, ideas, photos, videos, emails or other content  either directly to the Site or the Services (including to us through the Site or the Services) or through third party service providers.  While we generally would like to permit you to provide content to or through the Site or other Services, there are certain restrictions on your providing content.  They are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License:  You retain all ownership and copyrights in the content that you submit to us.  WE WILL NOT SELL YOUR CONTENT unless you have entered into a separate contract with us allowing us to do so; but by submitting content to us, you grant Richard Sumilang the right to post it on the Site, use it as part of the Services, use it for our internal purposes, and use it to promote Richard Sumilang (the Uses).  More specifically, by submitting content, you agree that we have a perpetual, non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free, irrevocable, fully and freely assignable and sub-licensable license to use the content for the Uses &amp;ndash; including, but not limited to, the rights to use, display, publish, translate, reproduce, distribute, modify, prepare derivative works based upon, and perform publicly your content (or any part thereof) online and offline in any form, media or technology now known or hereafter devised for purposes of the Uses. You further agree that Richard Sumilang and its licensees have the right to use your name and likeness in connection with Richard Sumilang publication, display, modification, distribution or other use of such content. Richard Sumilang is free to use any ideas, techniques, inventions, concepts, know-how, or other information that you provide to Richard Sumilang (whether directly or through its third party service providers) for purposes of the Uses without compensation or remuneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards:  You agree to tag racy, sexual, graphically violent, and/ or nude content that you submit as NSFW or Not Safe for Work. Failure to do so may result in your content being removed and/or suspension of your account. You agree not to submit any content that: (a) infringes on any third-party intellectual property, publicity, privacy, moral (droit moral) or other legal rights; (b) violates any applicable law or regulation; (c) is defamatory, threatening, harassing, obscene, harmful to minors, or child pornographic; (d) is false or misleading; (e) promotes physical or emotional harm in any way; (f) contains any viruses, Trojan horses, worms or other harmful components (including, but not limited to, computer programming routines that may damage, detrimentally interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system, data or personal information); (g) is commercial in nature, other than as specifically solicited by this Site; (h) constitutes unsolicited junk or bulk email (spam); or (i) is tortious or criminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warranty / Indemnity:  You warrant and guarantee that you own all intellectual property, proprietary, privacy, publicity, moral (droit moral) and other rights to any content that you submit.  You further agree to defend, indemnify, and hold us harmless against: (a) any and all claims to the rights to content that you provide, (b) any and all claims that someones rights were violated by our display or other use of the content that you provide to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring of Content / Removal:  You agree that Richard Sumilang has no responsibility to monitor, review, edit, remove or control any content or other information that you or others submit to us and/or the Site and/or the Services.  You further agree that Richard Sumilang may, in its sole discretion, modify, remove or refuse to accept any content for any reason.  We may also decline to modify or remove content that you submitted, despite your request.  In addition, please be aware that we may not be able to modify or remove certain content, including without limitation content that has been distributed to or relied on by third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Release:  You agree that you are at least 18 years of age.  You agree to release Richard Sumilang (including without limitation, for purposes of this Section C.5 of the Agreement, the officers, directors, employees, partners, limited partners, shareholders, owners, members, affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensors, licensees, third party contractors, agents, attorneys and representatives of Richard Sumilang) from any and all liability and obligations whatsoever in connection with or arising from Ricahrd Sumilang use or non-use of content submitted by you or any third party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy:  Other than as set forth in the Privacy Policy, Richard Sumilang may treat any submission and/or communication between you and Richard Sumilang as non-confidential and non-proprietary.  In particular, emails, comments concerning stories, letters, blog entries, social media correspondence from you, information from sources, and similar submissions will not be considered confidential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Endorsement / Recommendation:  Richard Sumilang does not endorse, recommend, or take any responsibility for any content submitted to the Services by you or any website visitor, account holder, advertiser, service provider, vendor, or other third-party, even if Richard Sumilang displays such content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;d-disclaimer-with-respect-to-advertisers-contractors-and-other-third-parties&#34;&gt;D. Disclaimer with respect to Advertisers, Contractors, and Other Third Parties&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang specifically disclaims all responsibility for the actions or inactions of advertisers, contractors, subcontractors, Web site developers and hosts, freelancers, licensors, licensees and other third parties that may contract with Richard Sumilang or its affiliates or may otherwise provide information or services to this Site or the Services, even if such third parties provide content to or linked to this Site or the Services  including, without limitation, the providers and third party users of any blogs, forums, chat rooms, personals, classifieds, and other features of this Site or the Services that are powered or provided by third parties.  You agree that your sole course of action with respect to such third parties will be against them directly.  You further agree that you will abide by the terms of use and privacy statements, if any, that they have provided for their website or services, but that in the event of a conflict between their terms and this Agreement, this Agreement applies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;e-disclaimer-with-respect-to-other-internet-sites&#34;&gt;E. Disclaimer with respect to Other Internet Sites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang has not reviewed all of the sites, or content of sites, that may be accessed from or linked to this Site or the Services.  Ruchard Sumilang is not responsible for the content of any pages or Internet images, information, or data, which are not contained on this Site or the Services.  Viewing of any and all other Web sites shall be at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;f-prohibition-on-use--enforcement-of-terms&#34;&gt;F. Prohibition on Use / Enforcement of Terms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang may at any time, for any reason, prohibit your further use in whole or in part of this Site or the Services.  We may also take any action that we deem necessary to enforce this Agreement, and to protect against unlawful or improper use of this Site or the Services.  You hereby expressly agree to waive any and all claims you may have (whether currently in existence and/or arising hereafter) against Richard Sumilang for any failure by us to enforce this Agreement, whether against you or a third party.  Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s failure to act in a particular circumstance does not waive its right to act with respect to that circumstance or other circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;g-access-limits&#34;&gt;G. Access Limits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s express consent, you may not frame any pages from the Site or the Services, place pop-up windows over pages of the Site or the Services, or otherwise affect the display of the Sites pages or of the Services.  Moreover, under no circumstances may you: (i) derive or attempt to derive the source or object code, source files or structure of this Site, the Services, or their content by reverse engineering, disassembly, decompilation or any other means; (ii) attempt to access the accounts of others, or attempt to penetrate security measures of the systems of Richard Sumilang or its affiliates or contractors (&amp;ldquo;hacking&amp;rdquo;), whether or not the intrusion results in corruption or loss of data; or (iii) transmit to Richard Sumilang or by means of this Site or the Services any unauthorized or unsolicited advertising, junk or bulk e-mail, or any other form of unauthorized or unsolicited transmission.  Richard Sumilang grants you permission to link to this Site (without framing it) or the Services, but may revoke this permission at any time for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain content or areas of the Site or Services may be marked NSFW or otherwise restricted.  You may not access that content or those areas unless you are of legal age to do so and are in compliance with any additional terms posted in association with those portions of the Site or Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;h-purchases&#34;&gt;H. Purchases&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be able to purchase video recordings, audio recordings, artwork, acrobat files, and information relating to such digital recordings, and other content (individually and collectively, Digital Content) and other products or services from the Site or Services. Such purchases are subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, including this &lt;strong&gt;Section H&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rights Granted:  Upon your payment of our fees for Digital Content, we grant you a perpetual, non-exclusive, non-transferable, non-sublicensable right to use the Digital Content for your personal, non-commercial, educational, or entertainment use. You may download, copy, store, transfer and burn the Digital Content only for your personal, non-commercial, educational or entertainment use. If you are unable to complete a download after payment is made, please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt; immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restrictions:  You represent, warrant and agree that you will use the Digital Content only for your personal, non-commercial, educational or entertainment use and not for any redistribution of the Digital Content or other use restricted in this &lt;strong&gt;Section H.2&lt;/strong&gt;. You agree not to infringe the rights of the Digital Content&amp;rsquo;s copyright owners and to comply with all applicable laws in your use of the Digital Content. Except as set forth in &lt;strong&gt;Section J.1&lt;/strong&gt; above, you agree that you will not redistribute, transmit, display, assign, sell, broadcast, rent, share, lend, modify, adapt, edit, license or otherwise transfer or use the Digital Content. You are not granted any synchronization, public performance, promotional use, commercial sale, resale, reproduction or distribution rights for the Digital Content. You acknowledge that the Digital Content embodies the intellectual property of a third party and is protected by law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Content and other products available through the Services are protected by federal Copyright Laws and any violation of these laws may subject the violator to civil liability and/or criminal prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risk of Loss:  You bear all risk of loss after purchase and for any loss of Digital Content you have downloaded, including any loss due to a computer or hard drive crash. We may, from time to time, remove Digital Content from the Service without notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;i--parental-control-provisions&#34;&gt;I.  Parental Control Provisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursuant to 47 U.S.C.  230(d), as amended, we hereby notify you that parental control protections (such as computer hardware, software, or filtering services) are commercially available that may assist you in limiting access to material that is harmful to minors.  Information identifying current providers of such protections is available at Get Net Wise, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getnetwise.org&#34;&gt;www.getnetwise.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;j-disclaimer-of-warranties-and-limitation-of-liability&#34;&gt;J. Disclaimer of Warranties and Limitation of Liability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOUR USE OF THIS SITE AND THE OTHER SERVICES IS AT YOUR OWN RISK.  THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED ON AN &amp;ldquo;AS IS&amp;rdquo; AND &amp;ldquo;AS AVAILABLE&amp;rdquo; BASIS.  RichardSumilang.com (including without limitation, for purposes of this Section J of the Agreement, Richard Sumilang and its officers, directors, employees, shareholders, partners, limited partners, owners, members, agents, affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensors, licensees, third party contractors, attorneys and representatives and any other parties involved in creating, producing or delivering this Site, the Services or any of the content, products or services available on or through this Site or the Services) HEREBY DISCLAIMS ALL EXPRESS AND/OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, RICHARD SUMILANG MAKES NO AND DISCLAIMS ANY REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED: (i) AS TO THE OPERATION OF THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES, (ii) AS TO THE INFORMATION, CONTENT, MATERIALS, SERVICES OR PRODUCTS INCLUDED ON OR AVAILABLE THROUGH THE SITE OR THE SERVICES; (iii) THAT THE SITE OR THE SERVICES WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE; (iv) AS TO THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY, OR CURRENCY OF ANY INFORMATION, CONTENT, SERVICE, OR MERCHANDISE PROVIDED ON OR THROUGH THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES; (v) THAT THE CONTENT OF THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES DOES NOT INFRINGE ON THE RIGHTS OF YOU OR THIRD PARTIES; AND/OR (vi) THAT THE SITE, THE SERVICES, THEIR SERVERS, OR E-MAIL SENT FROM OR ON BEHALF OF RICHARDSUMILANG.COM ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICHARD SUMILANG DOES NOT GUARANTY THE CONTINUOUS, UNINTERRUPTED OR SECURE ACCESS TO THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES.  THE OPERATION OF THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES MAY BE INTERFERED WITH BY NUMEROUS FACTORS OUTSIDE THE CONTROL OF RICHARD SUMILANG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES SHALL RICHARD SUMILANG BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR OTHER DAMAGES (OTHER THAN DIRECT DAMAGES) THAT RESULT FROM THE CONTENT OF, USE OF, OR INABILITY TO USE, THIS SITE, THE SERVICES, OR ANY DIGITAL CONTENT OR OTHER MERCHANDISE OBTAINED FROM THE SITE OR SERVIES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO RELIANCE BY A USER ON ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES AND/OR DAMAGES THAT RESULT FROM MISTAKES, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS, DELETION OF FILES OR EMAIL, ERRORS, DEFECTS, VIRUSES, DELAYS IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION, OR ANY FAILURE OF PERFORMANCE, WHETHER OR NOT RESULTING FROM ACTS OF GOD, COMMUNICATIONS FAILURE, THEFT, DESTRUCTION, OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO RICHARDSUMILANG.COM RECORDS, PROGRAMS, OR SERVICES.  THIS LIMITATION APPLIES WHETHER THE ALLEGED LIABILITY IS BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, NEGLIGENCE), INFRINGEMENT, OR ANY OTHER BASIS  EVEN IF RICHARD SUMILANG HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH LIABILITY.  WITH RESPECT TO DIRECT DAMAGES, YOUR REMEDY IS LIMITED TO A MAXIMUM OF ONE HUNDRED DOLLARS ($100) AND DISCONTINUANCE OF USE OF (AND ANY MEMBERSHIP IN) THIS SITE AND THE SERVICES.  YOU HEREBY ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THIS PARAGRAPH SHALL APPLY TO ALL CONTENT, MERCHANDISE, AND/OR SERVICES AVAILABLE ON OR THROUGH THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THESE DISCLAIMERS AND LIMITATIONS APPLY TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;k-indemnification&#34;&gt;K. Indemnification&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You agree to defend, indemnify, release and hold harmless Richard Sumilang (including without limitation, for purposes of this Section K of the Agreement, RichardSumilang.com, and its officers, directors, employees, shareholders, partners, limited partners, owners, members, agents, affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensors, licensees, third party contractors, attorneys and representatives and any other parties involved in creating, producing or delivering this Site, the Services or any of the content, products or services available on or through this Site or the Services) from all liabilities, claims and expenses, including attorneys fees and costs, that arise from, concern, or are connected with your use or misuse of this Site, the Services or any Digital Content or other merchandise that you obtain from the Site or Services.  Richard Sumilang reserves the right to assume the defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you, in which event you will cooperate with Richard Sumilang in asserting any available defenses and will pay all of RichardSumlang.com&amp;rsquo;s attorneys fees and costs in such defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;l-severability&#34;&gt;L. Severability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The provisions of this Agreement are intended to be severable.  If for any reason any provision of this Agreement shall be held invalid or unenforceable in whole or in part in any jurisdiction, such provision shall, as to such jurisdiction, be ineffective to the extent of such invalidity or unenforceability without in any manner affecting the validity or enforceability thereof in any other jurisdiction or the remaining provisions hereof in any jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;m-governing-law-and-jurisdiction&#34;&gt;M. Governing Law and Jurisdiction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You agree that the laws of the State of California will govern this Agreement and your use of this Site and the Services.  The state and federal courts of Los Angeles, California, shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any litigation that may arise out of, or be related to, this Agreement and/or your use of the Site or the Services.  You agree to waive any objection based on forum non conveniens or any objection to venue in Los Angeles, California, of any such action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;n-international-use&#34;&gt;N. International Use&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang makes no representation that this Site or the Services (including the content, services or products provided on or through them) are appropriate for or available to locations outside the United States of America; and using this Site or the Services from territories where it is illegal to do so is prohibited.  Any offer for a product or service through this Site or the Services is void where prohibited.  Use of this Site or the Services is done at your own risk and you are responsible for compliance with all local laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;o-assignment&#34;&gt;O. Assignment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You agree that this Agreement and all rights and licenses provided to Richard Sumilang under this Agreement are fully and freely assignable and sub-licensable by Richard Sumilang without further compensation to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;p-integration-and-modification&#34;&gt;P. Integration and Modification&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise specified herein or in a written agreement signed by Richard Sumilang, this Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between you and Richard Sumialng with respect to this Site, and supersedes all prior or contemporaneous communications or proposals between you and Richard Sumialng with respect to this Site and the Services.  You may not modify this Agreement other than by obtaining Richard Sumilang&amp;rsquo;s signed, written consent to such a modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;q-notice--contact&#34;&gt;Q. Notice / Contact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang can be contacted at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal notices shall be sent to the following address: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@richardsumilang.com&#34;&gt;me@richardsumilang.com&lt;/a&gt;. Notice will be considered given upon receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Sumilang is entitled to assume that any address information that you provide to us is correct, and Richard Sumilang may contact you at such address. Notice to you will be considered given when sent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Upgrading Emacs to 24.5
          
            - on Ubuntu 12.04
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/server/ubuntu/upgrade-emacs-to-24-5-on-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 46 Aug 5040 04:04:04 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/server/ubuntu/upgrade-emacs-to-24-5-on-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/server/ubuntu/upgrade-emacs-to-24-5-on-ubuntu-12-04/gnulogo-370x229.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dump this in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install checkinstall
mkdir -p ~/src
cd ~/src
wget https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/emacs-24.5.tar.gz
tar xf emacs-24.5.tar.gz
cd emacs-24.5
./configure
make
sudo checkinstall
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it a step further and install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syl20bnr/spacemacs&#34; title=&#34;Spacemacs&#34;&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
git clone https://github.com/syl20bnr/spacemacs ~/.emacs.d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          What are In-Ear Monitors?
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/in-ear-monitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 10010 01:01:01 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/electronics/audio/in-ear-monitors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In-Ear Monitors&lt;/em&gt; (IEMs), is a type of headphone designed to be partially
inserted into a user&amp;rsquo;s ear canal by using form-fitting tips often made by a
range materials such as rubber, soft plastic, silicon, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s also
common to purchase custom molded tips to fit your ear canal. This typically
offers the best results in comfort and noise isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may notice musicians typically wearing an IEM during a live performance.
This is to listen to a custom set of instruments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other names for IEMs are In-Ear-Canalphone, canalphone, or ear-canal headphone.
People believe the acronym IEM became the popular replacement for canalphones
with the iPod generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEMs are sometimes mistakenly called earbuds. The main difference being earbuds
are worn in the opening of the ear. They are not designed to sit in the ear
canal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        
          Facebook Page Analytics
          
            - with Ruby On Rails
          
        
      </title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/programming/ruby/ror/facebook-page-analytics-ror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 126 Aug 20120 12:12:12 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/posts/programming/ruby/ror/facebook-page-analytics-ror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to flex my programming muscle and try something new. I&amp;rsquo;ve done Ruby
for CLI tools and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/chef-gearman&#34; title=&#34;Chef-Gearman&#34;&gt;Chef cookbooks&lt;/a&gt; but never a Ruby on Rails (RoR)
application. Much of the hype with RoR is gone these days but it&amp;rsquo;s been around
long enough to be considered tested and somewhat mature like an old elitist
hipster&amp;hellip; If that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tldr;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/fb-page-analytics-ror&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Page Analytics with Ruby On Rails&#34;&gt;Just give me the source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was to create a Rails applications that provides analytics for the
last 100 Facebook posts of a Facebook page. As a user, you should be able to
login using Facebook, see a list of pages that you have authorized admin access
to, and lastly see a display of the pages&#39; top 5 posts (out of the last 100) as
well as a sortable table of the 100 most recent posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store user and page Facebook credentials, basic Facebook profile data (name of
user, name of page, email address), and the last 100 posts in a database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each entry in the post table should include:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link to Posts (on Facebook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Message/text body of post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Shares&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Likes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Impressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date Posted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts should be sortable by number of shares, likes, comments, and date posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Top 5 Posts&amp;rdquo; display can be chosen/ranked by any arbitrary combination of
post statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-application&#34;&gt;The Application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week long into RoR land and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say it&amp;rsquo;s done&amp;hellip; Well, 98% of it is.
I was nice enough to leave a little of this project left for you to do (I
happily accept pull requests):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrieving the number of impressions for each post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app currently does not paginate to the end of all Facebook page posts. It
stops at of the first set of results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/fb-page-analytics-ror&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Page Analytics with Ruby On Rails&#34;&gt;Facebook page analytics source&lt;/a&gt; is freely made available under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&#34; title=&#34;Creative Commons License 4.0&#34;&gt;Creative Commons License v4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-system&#34;&gt;My System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby:&lt;/strong&gt; ruby 2.2.1p85 (2015-02-26 revision 49769) [x86_64-darwin14]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rails:&lt;/strong&gt; Rails 4.2.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements to run the project will be kept updated in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsumilang/fb-page-analytics-ror/blob/master/README.rdoc&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Page Analytics Readme.rdoc&#34;&gt;README.rdoc&lt;/a&gt; but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t diverge too much from this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database setup (sqlite):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;Database Setup&#34;&gt;rake db:migrate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Facebook configuration variables are externalized via environment
variables so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set these parameters:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;Configuration&#34;&gt;export FB_APP_ID=YOUR_FB_APP_ID
export FB_APP_SECRET=YOUR_FB_APP_SECRET&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/apps/register&#34; title=&#34;Facebook Register and Configure an App&#34;&gt;Read this doc&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with created a Facebook App.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two servers need to be started. The &lt;em&gt;app server&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;job server&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; title=&#34;Servers&#34;&gt;rails s # app server
rake jobs:work # job server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;urls&#34;&gt;Urls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application:&lt;/strong&gt; http://localhost:3000/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Web View:&lt;/strong&gt; http://localhost:3000/delayed_job/overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the graphic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/programming/ruby/ror/facebook-page-analytics-ror/db-layout-772x346.png&#34; alt=&#34;Facebook Analytics Database Graphic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application can be loaded on http://localhost:3000/. You will find a
fancy &amp;ldquo;Facebook&amp;rdquo; link in the header. Click the link and log in with the test
account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon successful log in, the system grabs all the pages the user is an
administer of and does a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the page does not exist in our db then we create it and create the
relationship between the user and the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user no longer has access to a specific page then the relationship
between the two is removed but all page data is kept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pages controller will either list all the pages a user is an admin of,
allowing the user to choose OR redirect to the stats page of the single page
they administer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stats page is then responsible for retrieving all posts. On first load,
the stats page will pull from the top of the feed all the way down. On every
subsequent request, the stats controller will pull only newer feed items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A background job is then created for each post. This background job is
responsible for fetching the likes, comments, shares, and impressions for each
post while updating the database. This background process was created so the
wait on the stats page wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly long. Because of this, you will see the
stats update on the page when you refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stats page displays a top 5 list of the most popular posts. This is
ordered by date, likes, and comments. Nothing too crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stats page then lists all posts in a table below in a sortable fashion
by clicking the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign out button will set session variables to &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt; causing an invalid
session and redirect the user to the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gems-used&#34;&gt;Gems Used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following gems were used to build the project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mkdynamic/omniauth-facebook&#34; title=&#34;OmniAuth Facebook&#34;&gt;omniauth-facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Used to handle authentication to Facebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arsduo/koala&#34; title=&#34;Koala Gem&#34;&gt;koala&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Nifty for communicating with Facebook graph API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daemons.rubyforge.org/&#34; title=&#34;Daemons Gem&#34;&gt;daemons&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Experimented with this for fun. This would be used to run
the job server in production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/collectiveidea/delayed_job_active_record&#34; title=&#34;DelayedJob ActiveRecord Backend&#34;&gt;delayed_job_active_record&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; - Used to schedule and run the background
jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ejschmitt/delayed_job_web&#34; title=&#34;Delayed Job Web&#34;&gt;delayed_job_web&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Web interface for delayed job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;refactoring&#34;&gt;Refactoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I know that can be done better off the top of my head if
this were a real world application. (I would also appreciate any feedback or
ruby-isms in the comments.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally the stats page should not be making the request to Facebook to pull
in the posts associate with the page they are on. It should be a background job
that fires up more workers to gather the metrics for each post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job worker only supports handling one post at a time. It&amp;rsquo;s fine for the
sake example but in a real world situation we should be making batch requests.
This can easily be done by passing an array of Facebook &lt;code&gt;object_ids&lt;/code&gt; to the
endpoint to eliminate multiple requests. The same could be said for the page
controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the application grows, there will be more repetition the way things were
done. I can see use for breaking some of the &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; model up by removing the
sign up code and placing it into a concern and there can be good uses for
helpers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-thoughts&#34;&gt;End Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good:&lt;/strong&gt; I was fairly impressed with the amount of work I got done in a
short amount of time without having any Ruby friends to lean on. The syntactic
sugar provided by Ruby made certain things a pleasure to work with and gems seem
well thought out with a lot of care that the Ruby community is known for. My
personal favorite being the &lt;em&gt;delayed_job_active_record&lt;/em&gt; in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also impressed by how organized Rails is. The database migration feature
was really smooth and I thought it was neat how 3rd party gems made use of that
in your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bad:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes there was too much syntactic sugar that actually did the
opposite of making code easier to read. One of my pet peeves was using hashes.
This was because the colon placement in symbols changes and sometimes there
isn&amp;rsquo;t a clear distinction where a method parameter ends and starts without
having to look very closely. I found this annoying at times because it was also
hard for my IDE (IntelliJ) to tell me what was valid code. This is more of a
Ruby dislike than RoR, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Rails side, there was also too much magic. I get it, convention over
configuration but it bit me a few times with ActiveRecord. The code didn&amp;rsquo;t error
when trying to use so it was kind of annoying to debug at times. Maybe there are
better ways to do it that I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I use RoR again? Yeah, probably. The learning curve was kind of high with
Rails but once you get in the groove of it then it&amp;rsquo;s pretty powerful with the
amount of work you can accomplish in a short amount of time. For me, this would
be great for prototyping ideas. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the great gems I found and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rails-api/rails-api&#34; title=&#34;Rails::API&#34;&gt;Rails::API&lt;/a&gt; looks pretty neat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
