<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Audiophile on Top Secret Labs - Richard Sumilang</title>
    <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/tags/audiophile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Audiophile on Top Secret Labs - Richard Sumilang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 15:28:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.richardsumilang.com/tags/audiophile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Finest Audiophile Electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/work/losslesslife/the-worlds-finest-audiophile-electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 15:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/work/losslesslife/the-worlds-finest-audiophile-electronics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to announce &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;The world&#39;s finest Audiophile Electronics. Headphones, DACs, Amplifiers, reviews, and more.&#34;&gt;LosslessLife&lt;/a&gt;, a company focusing on the best
high resolution audio gear. LosslessLife reflects the continuous hard work
and commitment in the products it believes in by creating a voice to get the
word out from the audiophile communities and to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is often assumed by the average consumer that a higher price and/or bigger
brand name results in better product. While this can be true to some degree,
consumers are often paying more for a product&amp;rsquo;s marketing expenses when
purchasing from large retail stores rather than receiving higher performing
product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strict factors such as performance, output quality, and the overall
craftsmanship of products must be met in order to make it to LosslessLife as the
company name is synonymous with the highest level of quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a market that is saturated with mediocre products, LosslessLife believes it&amp;rsquo;s
success will be by educating consumers to make smarter choices when purchasing.
We do the research for you and provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;Covering everything from high-end and audiophile headphones. Headphones and headphone amplifiers, accessories, how-to guides, and reviews.&#34;&gt;all of the facts&lt;/a&gt; in an unbiased
fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many companies sell products which they claim they would use, LosslessLife
only sells products it does use by it&amp;rsquo;s highly enthusiastic team with
backgrounds in technology, production, and an affinity for music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bottlehead S.E.X. 2.1 Unboxed</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/electronics/bottlehead/sex/unboxed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 18:45:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/electronics/bottlehead/sex/unboxed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There you have it. All the parts that I&amp;rsquo;ll be assembling for the Bottlehead
S.E.X. version 2.1. The parts in the image include the impedance switch and the
C4S components. To the far left, there is a bag I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother unraveling
because it is mainly little screws and bolts that felt easy to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;build-order&#34;&gt;Build Order&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will do incremental builds. This way I can test the quality of a build on it&amp;rsquo;s
own before adding additional components. This is a good practice I follow in
daily software development and has proved helpful in debugging. The order will
be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S.E.X. kit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impedance switch installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C4S Upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bottlehead S.E.X. 2.1 Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/electronics/bottlehead/sex/bottlehead-sex-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 18:51:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/electronics/bottlehead/sex/bottlehead-sex-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After almost a month of waiting, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bottlehead.com/?product=single-ended-experimenters-kit-2-1-for-headphones-sensitive-speakers&#34; title=&#34;Bottlhead S.E.X. kit for Headphones and Sensitive Speakers&#34;&gt;Bottlehead S.E.X.&lt;/a&gt; has finally arrived.
This will be my first of many electronic DIY projects. I will detail the journey
from start to finish. Including details like what tools I used, any problems
I encountered, and any suggestions I come up with on the way. This blog series
is sort of like an enhancement to the original guide provided with your
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bottlehead.com/?product=single-ended-experimenters-kit-2-1-for-headphones-sensitive-speakers&#34; title=&#34;Bottlhead S.E.X. kit for Headphones and Sensitive Speakers&#34;&gt;Bottlehead S.E.X.&lt;/a&gt; purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>