<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Etcs on Richard Sumilang</title>
    <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Etcs on Richard Sumilang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 15:28:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Finest Audiophile Electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/work/losslesslife/the-worlds-finest-audiophile-electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 15:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/work/losslesslife/the-worlds-finest-audiophile-electronics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to announce &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;The world&#39;s finest Audiophile Electronics. Headphones, DACs, Amplifiers, reviews, and more.&#34;&gt;LosslessLife&lt;/a&gt;, a company focusing on the best
high resolution audio gear. LosslessLife reflects the continuous hard work
and commitment in the products it believes in by creating a voice to get the
word out from the audiophile communities and to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is often assumed by the average consumer that a higher price and/or bigger
brand name results in better product. While this can be true to some degree,
consumers are often paying more for a product&amp;rsquo;s marketing expenses when
purchasing from large retail stores rather than receiving higher performing
product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strict factors such as performance, output quality, and the overall
craftsmanship of products must be met in order to make it to LosslessLife as the
company name is synonymous with the highest level of quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a market that is saturated with mediocre products, LosslessLife believes it&amp;rsquo;s
success will be by educating consumers to make smarter choices when purchasing.
We do the research for you and provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.losslesslife.com/&#34; title=&#34;Covering everything from high-end and audiophile headphones. Headphones and headphone amplifiers, accessories, how-to guides, and reviews.&#34;&gt;all of the facts&lt;/a&gt; in an unbiased
fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many companies sell products which they claim they would use, LosslessLife
only sells products it does use by it&amp;rsquo;s highly enthusiastic team with
backgrounds in technology, production, and an affinity for music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMZ Mobile Website</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been an exciting journey from start to finish. As the head developer of
the mobile website for one of the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest blog sites, I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to
announce &lt;em&gt;Version 2&lt;/em&gt; of TMZ! Take a look at all the new features. I think you
will like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views and opinions shared in this article are those of the author&amp;rsquo;s (Richard
Sumilang) and do not necessarily reflect TMZ, Telepictures, Warner Bros and any
staff member or affiliate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/version-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 18:43:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/version-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rebuilt from the ground up, the new site is refined from the presentation to the
source. The theme has been modernized to load faster and I created more ways to
navigate the site so more data is easily accessible while keeping the idea of
simplicity in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;effective. Power&#34; ... An AOL Flashback.</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/apple/ios/effective-power-an-aol-flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 00:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/apple/ios/effective-power-an-aol-flashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richardsumilang.com/images/reactions/gamer/sp-hax0r.gif&#34; alt=&#34;haX0r&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a popular text message going around today that restarts a recipients
iPhone (if notifications is turned on) when they receive the following text:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
effective. 
Power
لُلُصّبُلُلصّبُررً ॣ ॣh ॣ ॣ
冗
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 18:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was just one of those days that started like any other. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a
lot of reflection over the past few weeks on what are my new goals. The act of
starting a new goal is always exciting but my life is pretty consistent despite
how random it seems. I always start off the day choosing one of my many similar
yet different shirts. Today I chose the shirt labeled Chocolate. I just wanted
someone to read &amp;ldquo;Chocolate&amp;rdquo; aloud so I can reply &amp;ldquo;Melts with in your mouth, not
in your hands.&amp;rdquo; Is that too much to ask for? (Who knows&amp;hellip;) So I go about my day
and start brushing up on PHP namespacing documents. I got some pretty useful
information out of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.php.net/manual/en/language.namespaces.basics.php#82088&#34; title=&#34;PHP Namespaces&#34;&gt;top comment&lt;/a&gt; and find out that it was written by me 6
years ago! It felt like the &lt;em&gt;past me&lt;/em&gt; was talking to &lt;em&gt;current me&lt;/em&gt;. A bit trippy
but also a bit embarrassing because I used to be on the bleeding edge of
software development &amp;gt;= 6 years ago. I then joined big corporations. The
technology was usually behind but I did learn a lot in terms of scalability and
working with agile teams. Now in my current role I have the opportunity to do
some really cool stuff which has been a bit of a refresh. It&amp;rsquo;s true what they
say, &amp;ldquo;if you don&amp;rsquo;t use it, you lose it&amp;rdquo;. But that&amp;rsquo;s ok as I was also focusing
more on other aspects in my life rather than just being an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day at TMZ</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/first-day-at-tmz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 21:49:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/first-day-at-tmz/</guid>
      <description>Today marks day 1 of my journey at TMZ. There is an exciting energy in this environment. The first thing you notice is an open workspace where there is action going on every minute. (You probably already know that if you&amp;rsquo;ve watched the show before.) The technology is also very impressive. The team no doubt consists of nothing but A+ players. How else would TMZ have gotten to be so big in a short amount of time?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just one of those days</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/just-one-of-those-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 19:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/just-one-of-those-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how beautiful the weather was today while returning home from brunch. The sky was a perfect blue, the winds were fresh but warm, and the sun was casting amazing shadows from the trees. One of those perfect weather day&amp;rsquo;s that you would kick yourself for staying in. As soon as I got home I pulled my bike out from the garage, wiped the spiders off, pumped up the wheels, and rode away. I always forget how happy it makes me to go out for a bike ride until I&amp;rsquo;m actually riding. So glad I did. :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world! ... Again.</title>
      <link>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/hello-world...again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 05:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.richardsumilang.com/etc/hello-world...again/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to bring back my blog in order to share technical notes and observations. I may carry over some content - particularly timeless posts - from my previous blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to begin a discussion on this blog, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to comment on the posts.
Without further adieu, welcome to my blog and don&amp;rsquo;t let the door hit you on the way out. ;)
Sincerely, Me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>